<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Central Asia’s Road to Stability</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/central-asia-fergana-valley-lesson-in-cross-border-stability-by-dan-sleat-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/central-asia-fergana-valley-lesson-in-cross-border-stability-by-dan-sleat-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fergana Valley offers lessons for other regions grappling with conflict and instability. By reopening their borders to each other and cooperating in the management of shared resources, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, and Uzbekistan have turned potential sources of conflict into sites of cooperation benefiting all.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Is Putin Silent on Venezuela?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-putin-thinks-of-the-us-operation-in-venezuela-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-putin-thinks-of-the-us-operation-in-venezuela-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Russian President Vladimir Putin certainly does not relish appearing weak, nor does he want to risk exacerbating tensions with the US. But his willingness to be pushed around has its limits, and it is entirely possible that Donald Trump's administration will prove pushy enough to find out what those limits are.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:05:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Gangster’s-Eye View of Global Power</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-donroe-doctrine-fuels-instability-and-jeopardizes-global-economy-by-jayati-ghosh-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-donroe-doctrine-fuels-instability-and-jeopardizes-global-economy-by-jayati-ghosh-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At the heart of US President Donald Trump’s foreign policy is the belief that the world can be carved up among major powers, with the United States free to act with impunity in its “backyard.” In reality, this approach is bound to fuel instability, fracture markets, and undermine America’s economic interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:22:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The World’s Two Largest Economies Should Slow Their Investment Race</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-quest-for-technological-supremacy-clashes-with-other-economic-goals-by-moreno-bertoldi-and-marco-buti-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-quest-for-technological-supremacy-clashes-with-other-economic-goals-by-moreno-bertoldi-and-marco-buti-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States and China are locked in a race for technological dominance, fueled by unprecedented investment. But this quest clashes with other economic objectives like lower inflation and financial stability, leaving both economies exposed to domestic pressures and global spillovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:05:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Anti-Moral Morality</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-might-makes-right-worldview-rules-out-moral-progress-by-peter-singer-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-might-makes-right-worldview-rules-out-moral-progress-by-peter-singer-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump now claims that the only thing that will stop him from doing as he pleases on the world stage is his own morality. Whether the world accepts Trump’s reversion to the unbridled dominance of great powers will determine the course of international relations for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:33:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe Enters the Slop War</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-fight-against-x-opening-salvo-of-war-for-democratic-debate-by-cori-crider-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-fight-against-x-opening-salvo-of-war-for-democratic-debate-by-cori-crider-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Inundated with manipulative slop that has warped public debate, the European Union has begun to confront the threat that social media platforms pose to democratic life. The fight ahead is not about free speech, as the United States contends, but about whether governments can rein in platforms that profit from disorder.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:11:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The AI We Need for Sustainable Infrastructure</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-potential-to-improve-infrastructure-investment-and-construction-by-bertrand-badre-and-saurabh-mishra-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-potential-to-improve-infrastructure-investment-and-construction-by-bertrand-badre-and-saurabh-mishra-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Even as governments pour trillions of dollars into roads, power grids, data centers, water systems, and housing, the construction industry has yet to leverage the efficiency gains that AI and digitalization have to offer. Given how important the sector will be for sustainable development, this must change.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe Is Stronger Than Its Leaders Think</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/european-leaders-must-not-mistake-success-for-failure-by-alberto-alemanno-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/european-leaders-must-not-mistake-success-for-failure-by-alberto-alemanno-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past three decades, the European Union has built a political and regulatory system strong enough to shape global competition and bind much of the continent together. Yet instead of doubling down, its leaders are weakening the social and economic model that made that achievement possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Last Days of Fed Independence?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/economic-costs-of-trump-efforts-to-politicize-monetary-policy-by-anne-o-krueger-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/economic-costs-of-trump-efforts-to-politicize-monetary-policy-by-anne-o-krueger-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump is again ratcheting up pressure on the Federal Reserve, this time with a criminal investigation of Fed Chair Jerome Powell, whose term ends in May. If Trump appoints a pliant successor, monetary policy will likely be looser than warranted, stoking inflation and undermining global economic stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:55:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The EU-Mercosur Deal Puts Principles into Practice</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-mercosur-agreement-why-it-matters-by-carlos-cuerpo-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-mercosur-agreement-why-it-matters-by-carlos-cuerpo-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By pushing through a long-awaited trade agreement with Mercosur (Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay, Uruguay), Europeans have demonstrated that they can manage their political differences and overcome resistance within and outside their borders. The values that the EU was built on are still alive.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:34:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grok Is Testing Whether AI Governance Means Anything</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/grok-sexualized-images-test-of-ai-governance-and-regulation-by-j-b-branch-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/grok-sexualized-images-test-of-ai-governance-and-regulation-by-j-b-branch-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By generating increasingly disturbing outputs, Grok has exposed a deep structural problem that should concern regulators everywhere. Advanced AI systems are being deployed and made available to the public without safeguards proportionate to their risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:22:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The High Cost of Trump’s Amateur Diplomats</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-costs-of-amateur-diplomacy-by-jan-werner-mueller-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-costs-of-amateur-diplomacy-by-jan-werner-mueller-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By sidelining professional diplomats in favor of amateurs who supposedly bring fresh thinking to the world’s most intractable conflicts, US President Donald Trump is channeling a long American tradition of anti-intellectualism. Inevitably, the United States will be made poorer, weaker, and more manipulable by adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The 2026 Outlook Calls for Recalibration</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/2026-outlook-investors-policymakers-will-need-to-recalibrate-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/2026-outlook-investors-policymakers-will-need-to-recalibrate-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The bullish AI narrative that dominated in 2025 is unlikely to continue overshadowing other lingering uncertainties, many of which reflect deeper structural shifts. Traditional factors underlying economic activity will be increasingly sidelined by national-security concerns, geopolitics, and domestic political machinations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Revenge of Global Imbalances</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-revenge-of-global-imbalances-by-barry-eichengreen-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-revenge-of-global-imbalances-by-barry-eichengreen-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Under France’s presidency of the G7, the club of rich countries will focus on major economies’ external deficits and surpluses. While the agenda makes sense politically, the economic case remains to be made.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:16:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are Central Banks Enabling Unsustainable Government Deficits?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-and-other-central-banks-enabling-unsustainable-deficits-by-raghuram-g-rajan-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-and-other-central-banks-enabling-unsustainable-deficits-by-raghuram-g-rajan-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent developments suggest that the US Federal Reserve's bond purchases are no longer just a "monetary operation," but an essential component of the US government's fiscal financing. The sooner that the Fed and other similarly situated central banks recognize the trap they have created for themselves, the better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ratcheting Up the Pressure on Afghanistan’s Gender Apartheid</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/un-must-pressure-taliban-afghanistan-codify-gender-apartheid-as-a-crime-by-gordon-brown-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/un-must-pressure-taliban-afghanistan-codify-gender-apartheid-as-a-crime-by-gordon-brown-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite recent efforts to make gender apartheid an international crime and to charge Afghanistan, countries have begun resuming relations with the Taliban regime. The United Nations must accelerate efforts to hold the Taliban accountable for its denial of girls’ and women’s rights, particularly their right to an education.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:56:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s Dwindling Maoist Insurgency</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-subdued-maoist-insurgency-by-investing-in-security-and-development-by-shashi-tharoor-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-subdued-maoist-insurgency-by-investing-in-security-and-development-by-shashi-tharoor-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;India’s violent Maoist insurgency – which at its 2013 peak, held considerable influence in 126 districts – appears to be on its last legs. This achievement attests to the power of a holistic and persistent development-driven approach to addressing complex internal security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why This Time Is Different for Iran</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-this-time-is-different-deadly-combination-internal-and-external-threats-by-vali-nasr-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-this-time-is-different-deadly-combination-internal-and-external-threats-by-vali-nasr-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For Iran's rulers, today's mass protests pose a vexing dilemma. Cracking down too hard could undo the entente that the regime forged with the population after last year's 12-day war with Israel and the United States, but letting them grow could itself invite foreign intervention.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Slain Mother and the Triumph of the Lie</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-officials-lying-about-renee-nicole-good-confers-maga-membership-by-stephen-holmes-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-officials-lying-about-renee-nicole-good-confers-maga-membership-by-stephen-holmes-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The killing of a 37-year-old Minneapolis mother by federal officials was certainly a tragedy and almost certainly a crime. But the administration’s response is something else: a demonstration that, in Donald Trump’s America, regurgitating obvious lies is how his followers and enablers prove that they belong.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Economic Roots of Iran’s Protests</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-protests-starting-december-28-response-to-economic-pressures-by-djavad-salehi-isfahani-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-protests-starting-december-28-response-to-economic-pressures-by-djavad-salehi-isfahani-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The protests now gripping Iran reflect, above all, economic grievances, which planned reforms are likely to exacerbate in the short term. Cash transfers and promises of lower inflation down the line are unlikely to be enough to appease a population battered by years of economic instability.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:29:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>