<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Neglected Solutions to Our Biggest Problems</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-change-middle-class-erosion-global-poverty-solutions-already-exist-by-dani-rodrik-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-change-middle-class-erosion-global-poverty-solutions-already-exist-by-dani-rodrik-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To rebuild the middle class, reduce global poverty, and address climate change simultaneously, we need to depart from established ways of thinking and consider new approaches. Fortunately, many of these approaches already exist at the local level, where they have proved themselves and need only to be recognized.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:15:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Polytunity</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/polycrisis-is-actually-opportunity-to-transform-global-development-paradigm-by-yuen-yuen-ang-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/polycrisis-is-actually-opportunity-to-transform-global-development-paradigm-by-yuen-yuen-ang-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Western leaders favor the language of “polycrisis” because it obscures the root cause of our current predicament: the industrial-colonial paradigm. Instead of focusing on fear, the world must study and tackle development challenges with a purposeful realism that draws on the creativity of a genuinely global community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:14:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In Russia, Enemies Are Everywhere</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-emulating-stalin-by-prosecuting-potential-rivals-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-emulating-stalin-by-prosecuting-potential-rivals-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Russians were promised a quick victory in Ukraine; instead, they have gotten a protracted and costly conflict reminiscent of the Afghan quagmire that contributed to the collapse of the Soviet Union. None of this is lost on President Vladimir Putin, who is ramping up prosecutions to eliminate potential rivals.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Courts Are Shaping the Future of Climate Action</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/legal-momentum-builds-toward-meaningful-climate-action-at-cop30-by-francesca-mascha-klein-and-laura-schafer-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/legal-momentum-builds-toward-meaningful-climate-action-at-cop30-by-francesca-mascha-klein-and-laura-schafer-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the absence of political will, the law has become a crucial driver of climate progress. Recent rulings make it clear that countries have binding legal duties to cut emissions, phase out fossil fuels, and finance adaptation efforts, laying the groundwork for stronger commitments at COP30.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Trump Ruling Like a King?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-ruling-like-a-king-but-still-can-be-checked-by-carla-norrlof-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-ruling-like-a-king-but-still-can-be-checked-by-carla-norrlof-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When millions of protesters came out this month to say, “No Kings,” Donald Trump posted an AI-generated video of himself being crowned, only to insist, the next day, that he is not a king. But how he sees himself ultimately matters less than how Congress, the courts, the business community, and the electorate do.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What AI Means for Growth and Jobs</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-will-boost-productivity-growth-without-harming-jobs-by-philippe-aghion-et-al-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-will-boost-productivity-growth-without-harming-jobs-by-philippe-aghion-et-al-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While many commentators warn that AI will undermine employment and offer only modest productivity gains, empirical studies continue to suggest otherwise. With the right policies in place, the technology holds immense potential to drive both growth and employment.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:20:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No Kings Means No Barons</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/no-kings-democracy-advocates-must-challenge-oligarchs-must-by-yanis-varoufakis-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/no-kings-democracy-advocates-must-challenge-oligarchs-must-by-yanis-varoufakis-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Turning the spotlight on the King while letting the barons off the hook will not stop Donald Trump and his copycats from amassing feudal powers. The illusion of the strong man who will fix everything cannot be dispelled by reviving the illusion that oligarchy offers the population democratic choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will AI Bury Future Generations in Cognitive Debt?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-destroying-traditional-career-automating-learning-by-doing-by-bertrand-badre-and-florian-ingen-housz-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-destroying-traditional-career-automating-learning-by-doing-by-bertrand-badre-and-florian-ingen-housz-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As companies seek to automate repetitive tasks in the name of cost-cutting, they should consider the longer-term implications. If we transfer all codified knowledge to machines, we will bequeath to future generations a world where it will be ever harder to learn by doing, to achieve mastery, and thus to aspire to creative freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:34:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How International Crises Help Authoritarians</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-war-helped-authoritarians-orban-hungary-erdogan-turkey-by-senem-aydin-duzgit-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-war-helped-authoritarians-orban-hungary-erdogan-turkey-by-senem-aydin-duzgit-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s increasingly multipolar world, the rise of geopolitical conflicts has been a boon for competitive authoritarian regimes. Russia’s war against Ukraine, for example, strengthened the domestic positions of Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orbán and Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan ahead of pivotal elections.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:42:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trump Could Win Over the Developing World</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-trump-administration-should-push-for-imf-sdr-not-swap-lines-by-vera-songwe-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-trump-administration-should-push-for-imf-sdr-not-swap-lines-by-vera-songwe-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At a time when developing countries are under fiscal pressure and struggling to invest in future growth, the United States could come to the rescue – and without putting one cent of its own money on the line. Rarely has there been a better moment for a new issuance of the International Monetary Fund's global reserve asset.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:01:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wall Street Risks Shorting Freedom in Hong Kong</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/hong-kong-banker-summit-while-pro-democracy-leaders-on-trial-by-mark-l-clifford-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/hong-kong-banker-summit-while-pro-democracy-leaders-on-trial-by-mark-l-clifford-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By attending a big investment summit in Hong Kong, Western financiers are showing what really drives them. The only conclusion to draw is that they are willing to chase short-term profits even if it means funding a repressive regime that has made no secret of its animosity toward the West.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:29:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Case for a Multilateral Trade Organization Without America</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/major-trading-countries-should-adopt-carney-proposal-for-new-coalition-by-anne-o-krueger-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/major-trading-countries-should-adopt-carney-proposal-for-new-coalition-by-anne-o-krueger-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s divide-and-rule tactics have shattered the postwar multilateral order. To preserve open, rules-based commerce, America’s major trading partners must form a new coalition capable of upholding the principles that the World Trade Organization can no longer guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China Needs a Consumption Target</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-five-year-plan-must-set-target-for-household-consumption-as-share-of-gdp-by-stephen-s-roach-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-five-year-plan-must-set-target-for-household-consumption-as-share-of-gdp-by-stephen-s-roach-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As Chinese leaders prepare the 15th Five-Year Plan, early signs indicate that it will focus on continuing China’s extraordinary technological ascendancy. But they should be more concerned with boosting consumer demand, which means setting a clear target of raising household consumption to 50% of GDP by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:07:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Trump Achieve Eternal Peace in Gaza?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-gaza-ceasefire-many-questions-unanswered-by-joschka-fischer-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-gaza-ceasefire-many-questions-unanswered-by-joschka-fischer-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is the only power that can succeed as a peacemaker in the Middle East; but that doesn’t mean the task will be easy. The question now is whether US President Donald Trump has the patience and stamina that brokering a lasting political resolution between Israelis and Palestinians requires.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Trump Administration’s Latest Assault on Workers</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-refusal-to-defend-ban-on-non-compete-clauses-hurts-workers-by-sandeep-vaheesan-and-alvaro-bedoya-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-refusal-to-defend-ban-on-non-compete-clauses-hurts-workers-by-sandeep-vaheesan-and-alvaro-bedoya-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024, the US Federal Trade Commission freed millions of Americans from a powerful constraint on their labor-market mobility by banning non-compete clauses for most workers. It was one of the biggest policy wins for American workers in recent years – and, because of Donald Trump's administration, it may never take effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Perils of Economic Centrism in a Polarized World</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/loneliness-of-the-centrist-economist-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/loneliness-of-the-centrist-economist-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Few ideas in economics have been as misrepresented as the link between debt and growth. More than a decade ago, a prominent analysis was falsely cast as a call for austerity when, in fact, it showed something far more mundane: countries burdened by heavy debt often have limited room to invest or respond when crises strike.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Geopolitical Significance of Historical Precedent</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/historical-precedents-for-geopolitical-uncertainty-can-help-shape-response-by-jacques-attali-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/historical-precedents-for-geopolitical-uncertainty-can-help-shape-response-by-jacques-attali-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The cycle of rise and decline over the centuries has established some basic tenets of power, including that civilizations can still collapse even when they are set up for success. This lesson is relevant for today’s world, in which short-termism and populism risk derailing what should be a bright future.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:10:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The German Economic Miracle, Then and Now</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/german-postwar-economic-miracle-revisited-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/german-postwar-economic-miracle-revisited-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Why did Germany, defeated in both World War I and WWII, recover so strongly after the latter, but not after the former? Two new books suggest that conventional accounts of the Wirtschaftswunder – West Germany’s miraculous economic ascent after WWII – get it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:42:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine Needs a “Victory First” Aid Strategy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-allies-must-finance-military-defense-spending-by-anastassia-fedyk-et-al-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-allies-must-finance-military-defense-spending-by-anastassia-fedyk-et-al-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Western countries have been generous in supporting Ukraine since Russia’s full-scale invasion in 2022, their financial assistance can be used only for non-military purposes. Instead of deploying aid this way, which creates distortions that undermine Ukraine’s war effort, foreign donors should directly fund defense spending.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Africans Want from COP30</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-must-present-a-united-front-at-cop30-by-carlos-lopes-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-must-present-a-united-front-at-cop30-by-carlos-lopes-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of continuing to wait for aid, Africa is seeking to mobilize investment in its green transition, not because rich countries “owe” Africans – though they do – but because Africa can help the world tackle climate change. Success will require progress on four fronts, all of which will be addressed at COP30.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>