<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>What Can Europe Offer a Fragmenting World?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-update-value-proposition-to-bolster-global-standing-by-ngaire-woods-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-update-value-proposition-to-bolster-global-standing-by-ngaire-woods-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the rivalry between the United States and China intensifies, many countries are seeking partners they can trust. The European Union could fill that role by offering economic opportunity, a secure investment environment, and legal systems that are predictable and fair.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can the Developing World Weather the Next Financial Crisis?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-could-be-hit-hardest-by-future-financial-crisis-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-could-be-hit-hardest-by-future-financial-crisis-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As asset prices soar and speculative money floods into risky markets, the global financial system is slipping back into perilous territory. When the inevitable correction arrives, the fallout will spread far beyond the United States and Europe, hitting developing economies already weighed down by debt and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Argentina Is on a Path to Economic Success</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/javier-mileis-economic-reforms-will-deliver-with-electoral-uncertainty-removed-by-nouriel-roubini-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/javier-mileis-economic-reforms-will-deliver-with-electoral-uncertainty-removed-by-nouriel-roubini-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While many commentators have criticized Argentine President Javier Milei's draconian approach to economic reform, the results of the October legislative election show that the Argentine people would prefer short-term economic pain over a return to Peronist policies. Milei now has a clear path to finish what he started.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:26:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASEAN’s Moment of Truth</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/asean-reforms-to-strengthen-stability-and-prosperity-by-mari-elka-pangestu-and-tan-sri-rebecca-fatimah-sta-maria-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/asean-reforms-to-strengthen-stability-and-prosperity-by-mari-elka-pangestu-and-tan-sri-rebecca-fatimah-sta-maria-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the Asian financial crisis of the 1990s to the COVID-19 pandemic, the bloc has so far risen to the challenges it has faced. But it now confronts its biggest test yet: building balanced partnerships with powerhouses like China, India, Japan, and the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is the Gold Price Telling Us?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-do-record-gold-prices-mean-by-jim-o-neill-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-do-record-gold-prices-mean-by-jim-o-neill-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the price of gold hitting new records and pulling back sharply, is it a bubble or a sign of some profound, broader change in the global financial landscape? While the answer is anyone's guess, history does offer some clues.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Violent New Monroe Doctrine</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-intervention-in-latin-america-reflects-a-new-and-volatile-monroe-doctrine-by-ana-palacio-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-intervention-in-latin-america-reflects-a-new-and-volatile-monroe-doctrine-by-ana-palacio-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US airstrikes in the Caribbean reflect President Donald Trump’s view of intra-American relations as hierarchical. Whereas previous US presidents tried to reconcile Woodrow Wilson’s idealism with Theodore Roosevelt’s realism, Trump merges both impulses into a single, volatile creed: exceptionalism without responsibility or restraint.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:18:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What COP30 Must Do</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cop30-must-follow-financing-commitments-with-concrete-plans-by-syeda-rizwana-hasan-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cop30-must-follow-financing-commitments-with-concrete-plans-by-syeda-rizwana-hasan-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whereas last year’s United Nations Climate Change Conference tripled the global climate-finance target, this year’s gathering must show how funds will be delivered. Developing countries are doing their part, but their climate strategies cannot succeed without external support.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Bessent Right About the Fed?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-bessent-right-about-the-fed-by-willem-h-buiter-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-bessent-right-about-the-fed-by-willem-h-buiter-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The US Federal Reserve and most other G7 central banks have made numerous policy errors this century, making them ripe targets for criticism. But while reforms are necessary to improve their monetary-policy and regulatory performance, that does not mean their independence should be curtailed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Politics Are a Family Business</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-prevalence-of-political-dynasties-lead-to-worse-governance-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-prevalence-of-political-dynasties-lead-to-worse-governance-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The belief that members of political dynasties are uniquely suited to lead is woven deeply into the fabric of Indian governance, from village councils to the highest echelons of parliament. But when elected office is treated like a family heirloom, the quality of governance inevitably suffers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:20:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Lie Behind Trump’s Boat Strikes</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-big-lies-drug-boat-strikes-venezuela-by-timothy-snyder-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-big-lies-drug-boat-strikes-venezuela-by-timothy-snyder-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is training the press and the American people to associate the military strikes on small boats in international waters with stopping the flow of fentanyl and other drugs. This mendacity is a prime example of the falsehoods that imperialists tell before launching doomed wars of aggression.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:40:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Coming US-China Thaw</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-thaw-rare-earths-ban-shows-american-aggression-no-longer-works-by-james-k-galbraith-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-thaw-rare-earths-ban-shows-american-aggression-no-longer-works-by-james-k-galbraith-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of increasingly hostile rhetoric from US officials about China, highly authoritative voices in the United States have suddenly become less hawkish, and the Trump administration has begun to pursue new trade negotiations in earnest. Is the American establishment finally waking up to economic reality?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Development Finance Must Shift Away from Aid</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-must-reduce-foreign-aid-dependence-by-justin-yifu-lin-and-yan-wang-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-must-reduce-foreign-aid-dependence-by-justin-yifu-lin-and-yan-wang-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As traditional donors slash foreign-aid budgets, developing countries must mobilize a broader range of financing sources. National development banks, sovereign wealth funds, debt swaps, and public-private partnerships can foster sustainable investment and help reduce energy poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:13:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Vulnerable Is China?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/how-vulnerable-is-china</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/how-vulnerable-is-china</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The meeting between US President Donald Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping may have delivered a kind of détente, after months of escalating tariff threats by the United States and retaliatory restrictions on rare-earth exports by China. While China had good reason to de-escalate the conflict with the US, however, it remains beset by political and economic weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:08:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Picture</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-vulnerable-is-china-doc-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-vulnerable-is-china-doc-2025-10</guid><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:07:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Pivot from Asia</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-pivot-from-asia-to-western-hemisphere-by-richard-haass-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-pivot-from-asia-to-western-hemisphere-by-richard-haass-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After US President Donald Trump's trip to the region, one could be forgiven for concluding that the "pivot to Asia" begun when Barack Obama was in the White House has been replaced by a pivot to the Western Hemisphere. Needless to say, this is not the pivot America’s friends and allies in Asia were and are counting on.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can China Catch Up with the US Economically?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-will-avoid-the-middle-income-trap-but-fail-to-outgrow-the-us-economy-by-keun-lee-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-will-avoid-the-middle-income-trap-but-fail-to-outgrow-the-us-economy-by-keun-lee-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With its GNI per capita having increased steadily in recent years, China has probably evaded the middle-income trap. But the country may yet find itself ensnared in a kind of economic Thucydides trap: attempting to surpass an incumbent hegemon bent on keeping it down – and never quite succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will AI Kill the Firm?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ai-rewriting-rules-of-modern-capitalism-by-sami-mahroum-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ai-rewriting-rules-of-modern-capitalism-by-sami-mahroum-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For centuries, the firm has organized economic life, translating human labor into value through hierarchy and routine. But as agentic AI begins to perform the managerial work of coordinating and decision-making, the institutions that once defined modern capitalism are starting to give way.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:20:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Supporters Should Be Careful What They Wish For</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/supreme-court-should-uphold-challenge-to-trump-tariffs-by-simon-johnson-and-stan-a-veuger-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/supreme-court-should-uphold-challenge-to-trump-tariffs-by-simon-johnson-and-stan-a-veuger-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If the US Supreme Court upholds President Donald Trump's use of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to impose tariffs on US allies and adversaries alike, it will hand a loaded gun to future presidents. Why couldn't an administration use IEEPA tools to enforce a global minimum corporate tax or effectively ban crypto trading?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Trouble with Abundance</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democrats-cannot-build-a-political-strategy-on-abundance-by-jeffrey-frankel-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democrats-cannot-build-a-political-strategy-on-abundance-by-jeffrey-frankel-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a book released earlier this year, Ezra Klein and Derek Thompson argue essentially for “competent capacity”: a US that can effectively plan, approve, and execute projects. That is a worthy goal, but “abundance” is probably not the clearest way to convey it, let alone the most effective means of achieving it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:27:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Social Protection Can Accelerate Climate Action</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cop30-should-integrate-climate-goals-into-inclusive-social-protection-systems-by-tracy-kajumba-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cop30-should-integrate-climate-goals-into-inclusive-social-protection-systems-by-tracy-kajumba-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report shows that the integration of climate objectives and social-protection systems can go a long way toward delivering finance where it is needed most. But making the most of these findings will require a new approach to designing, financing, and implementing social-protection programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>