<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Europeans Are All Peronists Now</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-implement-necessary-reforms-budget-cuts-to-avoid-argentina-fate-by-cristina-ramirez-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-implement-necessary-reforms-budget-cuts-to-avoid-argentina-fate-by-cristina-ramirez-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;European voters increasingly resemble their Argentinian counterparts, who, until recently, believed the unsustainable promises offered by Peronist politicians. To avoid the economic shock therapy that has befallen Argentina, Europe’s leaders must be willing to make hard choices, and electorates must be willing to reward them for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gen Z Is Making Politics Hopeful Again</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/young-people-are-demanding-future-worth-living-by-ngaire-woods-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/young-people-are-demanding-future-worth-living-by-ngaire-woods-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fueled by anger over corruption, high living costs, and narrowing opportunities, youth-led protests have been sweeping the developing world. Rather than seeking to upend political systems, activists are calling for governments that deliver economic security, accountability, and climate action.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump Has an Affordability Problem</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-affordability-problem-assigning-blame-by-michael-r-strain-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-affordability-problem-assigning-blame-by-michael-r-strain-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although Americans are rightly worried about inflation and the affordability of basic goods and services, much of the commentary on the issue has offered more heat than light. How much blame does the president deserve, and what could he do to stave off electoral disaster in November 2026?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:19:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Fed Became a Lender of Immediate Resort</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-mission-creep-undermines-its-legitimacy-by-amit-seru-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-mission-creep-undermines-its-legitimacy-by-amit-seru-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With each crisis over the past 15 years, the Federal Reserve has expanded the scope and scale of its interventions. This gradual mission creep has blurred the line between routine liquidity support and support for insolvent institutions, undermining the very purpose of central-bank independence.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rogue Hegemons Are Sabotaging the Global Economy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-chinese-mercantilism-upending-global-trading-system-by-arvind-subramanian-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-chinese-mercantilism-upending-global-trading-system-by-arvind-subramanian-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than providing global public goods, the United States and China are inflicting global economic costs –&amp;nbsp;in mutually reinforcing ways. Donald Trump's tariffs have exacerbated Chinese mercantilism, and Chinese exports are provoking developing countries to engage in protectionism of their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:51:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Model to Keep Multilateralism Alive</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/gavi-model-can-sustain-multilateral-cooperation-by-jose-manuel-barroso-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/gavi-model-can-sustain-multilateral-cooperation-by-jose-manuel-barroso-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the world becomes more multipolar, geopolitical tensions are hampering efforts to devise common solutions to shared problems, and developments within many countries are threatening the institutions on which multilateralism depends. Mission-driven, public-private partnerships like Gavi may offer the only way forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporate AI Is a Threat to Freedom</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/corporate-ai-threat-to-freedom-algorithmic-manipulation-by-richard-k-sherwin-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/corporate-ai-threat-to-freedom-algorithmic-manipulation-by-richard-k-sherwin-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If AI remains under the control of profit-maximizing firms, liberal democracy could become an illusion. The public urgently needs to understand that freedom depends on defending human agency from incursions by machines designed to shape thinking and feeling in ways that favor corporate, rather than human, flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:05:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expect Turbulent Asset Markets in 2026</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/powerful-headwinds-facing-global-economy-in-2026-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/powerful-headwinds-facing-global-economy-in-2026-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After three years of extraordinary returns, investors should start worrying about the inevitable crash that follows periods of sustained euphoria. But while the odds of a major market correction in the next few years appear uncomfortably high, heading for the exits now could be premature.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:13:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Shocks that Shook the World in 2025</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/three-shocks-in-2025-leave-europe-shaken-by-yanis-varoufakis-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/three-shocks-in-2025-leave-europe-shaken-by-yanis-varoufakis-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new, harder, colder world order was erected on the grave of European ambition in 2025. The year’s enduring lesson is that in an age of existential contests, strategic dependency is the prelude to irrelevance.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe’s Carbon Market Must Look Ahead</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/economic-case-for-european-carbon-market-by-gunther-thallinger-and-ludovic-subran-1-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/economic-case-for-european-carbon-market-by-gunther-thallinger-and-ludovic-subran-1-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Since its creation, Europe’s carbon market has delivered significant emissions cuts, directed substantial resources toward clean-energy technologies, and become a model for other systems worldwide. But rising energy prices are fueling political pressure to relax carbon pricing, which would be a grave mistake.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:17:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The AI Diffusion Challenge</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/whether-ai-meets-expectations-depends-on-diffusion-and-policy-support-by-michael-spence-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/whether-ai-meets-expectations-depends-on-diffusion-and-policy-support-by-michael-spence-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While investors seem, by and large, to be betting on a massive payoff from today's AI spending, some predict that the technology will fall short of expectations, leading to a bust. Who turns out to be right will depend far more on diffusion than on frontier development.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Donald Trump and the White Man’s Burden in Nigeria</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-threats-to-invade-nigeria-reflect-colonizers-civilizing-mission-by-adekeye-adebajo-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-threats-to-invade-nigeria-reflect-colonizers-civilizing-mission-by-adekeye-adebajo-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump recently threatened to take military action against Nigeria to save Christians from a “genocide.” Trump has three possible motives for making such a threat: his mercantilist quest for rare-earth minerals, his pandering to evangelical Christians, and his racist grievances.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global Health Workers Strengthen US National Security</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-must-continue-funding-community-health-workers-africa-pepfar-by-junaid-nabi-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-must-continue-funding-community-health-workers-africa-pepfar-by-junaid-nabi-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The US government’s new global health strategy calls for shifting 270,000 frontline health-care workers from US-funded NGO programs to recipient government payrolls. But this could cause an exodus from the profession, undermining the disease-surveillance system and putting American lives at risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:07:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Big, Not-So-Beautiful Economic Mess</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-first-year-back-leaves-his-economic-agenda-in-trouble-by-anne-o-krueger-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-first-year-back-leaves-his-economic-agenda-in-trouble-by-anne-o-krueger-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite US President Donald Trump’s promises to lower inflation, shrink deficits, and revive manufacturing, his tariff wars have imposed steep costs on key allies, triggered price spikes, and hurt American producers and farmers. Yet there is little evidence that Trump is prepared to change course.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:08:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The AI War on Christmas</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-turns-christmas-songs-sacred-carols-into-slop-by-timothy-snyder-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-turns-christmas-songs-sacred-carols-into-slop-by-timothy-snyder-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;American politics has latched onto the idea that Christmas has somehow been sullied by foreigners, particularly non-Christians. In fact, the holiday has been corrupted by non-human entities: a set of algorithms that we flatteringly call artificial intelligence has desecrated the season’s music and holiday ritual.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:02:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PS Commentators’ Best Reads in 2025</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ps-commentators-best-reads-2025-by-ps-editors-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ps-commentators-best-reads-2025-by-ps-editors-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As technological advances and geopolitical turmoil transform our economies, this year’s recommended books challenge prevailing assumptions and prompt us to reconsider what we take for granted. Ranging from scholarly analyses to literary fiction, they illuminate the choices that will define the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:45:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s Civilizational Suicide</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-national-security-strategy-rejects-western-values-by-carl-bildt-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-national-security-strategy-rejects-western-values-by-carl-bildt-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By heaping abuse on Europe and handling Russia and China with kid gloves, the Trump administration's National Security Strategy represents a radical departure from past US policies. But even as America rejects everything it once stood for, Europeans' only choice is to double down on their own principles.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:49:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil’s Bold Industrial Turn</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/brazil-lula-reindustrialization-gamble-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/brazil-lula-reindustrialization-gamble-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite strong opposition in Congress, Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva has launched an ambitious industrial policy aimed at boosting renewable-energy capacity and expanding domestic defense capabilities. But sky-high interest rates and fiscal constraints risk putting these objectives out of reach.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:13:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Transatlantic Rupture Is Complete</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-imperial-dreams-and-transatlantic-rupture-by-joschka-fischer-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-imperial-dreams-and-transatlantic-rupture-by-joschka-fischer-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Under President Donald Trump, the United States is seeking to create a world order based solely on spheres of interest controlled by the US, China, and Russia. And because this will require breaking up the European Union, the decades-long transatlantic alliance has given way to enmity in remarkably short order.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:15:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Decision Time for Europe</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-plan-for-ukraine-postwar-scenario-on-its-own-by-mark-leonard-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-plan-for-ukraine-postwar-scenario-on-its-own-by-mark-leonard-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Given the Trump administration’s recent statements and policy pronouncements, European leaders no longer have any excuse for failing to map out their own long-term security strategy. If they can get their act together on ending the Ukraine war, they will gain a much stronger position on other key fronts, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:43:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>