<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>The Political Logic of Trump’s Violent Lawlessness</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ice-killings-minnesota-moral-horror-but-also-shows-trumps-political-logic-by-timothy-snyder-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ice-killings-minnesota-moral-horror-but-also-shows-trumps-political-logic-by-timothy-snyder-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The moral horror of ICE and Border Patrol agents executing US citizen observers is enough to denounce the Trump administration’s campaign of cruelty in Minnesota. But it is also important to recognize how it reflects the political logic of turning an entire country into a lawless border zone.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 09:43:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MAGA Is Destroying the Culture that Built the West</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-trump-destroying-culture-that-built-the-west-by-j-p-singh-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-trump-destroying-culture-that-built-the-west-by-j-p-singh-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of the West is a simple story to tell culturally: It’s about Europe moving toward openness, cosmopolitanism, intellectual freedom, transparent rules, and, above all, institutional checks and balances. US President Donald Trump negates these values at every turn.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bloody Minnesota</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/minneapolis-ice-killings-political-turning-point-for-us-by-daron-acemoglu-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/minneapolis-ice-killings-political-turning-point-for-us-by-daron-acemoglu-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The killings of two innocent civilians –&amp;nbsp;both US citizens – by federal immigration agents in Minneapolis this month may mark a turning point for the United States. The energy and solidarity among people supporting their immigrant neighbors and protesting ICE’s brutal tactics herald a defining showdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:38:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where Does Europe Go From Here?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-trump-greenland-resolution-lessons-to-take-from-davos-by-mark-leonard-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-trump-greenland-resolution-lessons-to-take-from-davos-by-mark-leonard-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Beyond showcasing Donald Trump's "neo-royalist" style of politics, this year's annual gathering of the global elite in Davos revealed deeper, structural changes that will shape political and business leaders’ decision-making for years to come. Europeans, in particular, must absorb the right lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:55:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stifling the “Spirit of Dialogue” at Davos</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/world-economic-forum-meeting-davos-appeases-trump-ignores-climate-change-by-hippolyte-fofack-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/world-economic-forum-meeting-davos-appeases-trump-ignores-climate-change-by-hippolyte-fofack-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The World Economic Forum chose “A Spirit of Dialogue” as the theme for this year’s meeting in Davos. But, to secure US President Donald Trump’s participation, the organization agreed to avoid “woke” topics such as the energy transition, preventing any meaningful exchange on the urgent need for climate action.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:14:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tariffs Are More Destructive Than You Think</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariffs-costs-and-damage-to-economy-greater-than-many-understand-by-sebnem-kalemli-ozcan-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariffs-costs-and-damage-to-economy-greater-than-many-understand-by-sebnem-kalemli-ozcan-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s interconnected global economy, tariffs produce outcomes that are very different from what traditional economic models would predict. Rather than causing only limited and temporary distortions, tariffs can generate persistent inflation, significant output losses, and damaging international spillovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Has Abandoned the World</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-withdrawal-from-international-organizations-is-harmful-not-popular-by-gordon-brown-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-withdrawal-from-international-organizations-is-harmful-not-popular-by-gordon-brown-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s decision to withdraw the United States from 66 international organizations is ostensibly aimed at cutting waste, but the inclusion of agencies supporting girls and women underscores the move’s arbitrariness and vindictiveness. It will have dire consequences for people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI Could Restore Trust in Democratic Governance</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-ai-could-restore-trust-democratic-governance-by-sami-mahroum-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-ai-could-restore-trust-democratic-governance-by-sami-mahroum-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The key to success for high-trust technocracies like Singapore and the United Arab Emirates is that they have figured out how to deliver visible policy results while remaining responsive to ever-evolving public concerns. Now, new AI tools help low-trust democracies do the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:40:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Time Has Come to Shutter the World Economic Forum</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/davos-world-economic-forum-serves-no-beneficial-purpose-by-katharina-pistor-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/davos-world-economic-forum-serves-no-beneficial-purpose-by-katharina-pistor-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a place where political and business leaders can enjoy one another’s company, the World Economic Forum's annual Davos gathering has been an incubator for standards that have shaped the global economy. But the Davos order is now crumbling, and if regular attendees had bothered to consult ordinary people, they might understand why.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:06:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American Democracy After Trump</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/american-democracy-after-maga-trumpism-by-mordecai-kurz-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/american-democracy-after-maga-trumpism-by-mordecai-kurz-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;America's current dysfunction - as exemplified by Trumpism and the decline of democracy - stems from the massive rise of private power and the deep inequalities it has produced. As the root causes of everything that has gone wrong since the 1980s, these are where any project of national rejuvenation must begin.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is China’s Economic Policy Too Cautious?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-economic-policy-must-address-entrenched-imbalances-by-lee-jong-wha-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-economic-policy-must-address-entrenched-imbalances-by-lee-jong-wha-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recognizing that the old growth model has run its course, China’s leaders have embraced a measured economic strategy, focused on “high-quality development,” stability, and risk management. But they must not be so cautious that they fail to address the imbalances that may become hard constraints on the economy's long-term prospects.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:16:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI and the Future of Education</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-future-of-education-by-pinelopi-koujianou-goldberg-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-future-of-education-by-pinelopi-koujianou-goldberg-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The central challenge for educators in the age of AI is to prepare students to operate effectively in the face of uncertainty. The answer is not to train them for specific tasks that may soon become obsolete, but to make them as adaptable and intellectually independent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:40:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Appeasing Trump Only Invites Betrayal - as Europe’s Far Right Just Learned</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-greenland-shows-that-only-interest-is-in-domination-and-others-self-abasement-by-stephen-holmes-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-greenland-shows-that-only-interest-is-in-domination-and-others-self-abasement-by-stephen-holmes-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Trump laying claim to Greenland, Europeans have finally realized who they are dealing with. The US president is animated less by the prospect of deal-making than by the need for domination, less by the spirit of exchange than by the perverse pleasure of belittling others and exalting himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why AI Is Unlike Previous Tech Booms</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-boom-rewrites-tech-industry-playbook-by-dambisa-moyo-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-boom-rewrites-tech-industry-playbook-by-dambisa-moyo-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of AI follows a fundamentally different competitive logic than earlier technological revolutions. With massive capital requirements, high operating expenses, low switching costs, and intensifying regulatory scrutiny, success will depend less on scale and more on financial resilience and political influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scott Bessent Is in Denial – and the Bond Market Is Watching</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/scott-bessent-is-underestimating-the-risk-of-a-us-treasury-selloff-by-desmond-lachman-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/scott-bessent-is-underestimating-the-risk-of-a-us-treasury-selloff-by-desmond-lachman-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Far from warning Donald Trump against undermining foreign investors’ confidence in the US, his Treasury secretary is backing the president and downplaying the risks of a bond selloff. But markets are telling a different story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:33:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Imperialism Without Alibis</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/donald-trump-imperalism-without-alibis-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/donald-trump-imperalism-without-alibis-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By asserting control over Venezuela’s primary sources of revenue, US President Donald Trump has replaced the moral rhetoric of his predecessors with a 21st-century version of colonial-era indirect rule. The result is a country that retains the symbols of self-government but functions as an American protectorate.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:57:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Philanthropy Must Dive Deeper to Save the Ocean</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/philanthropy-can-help-unlock-financing-necessary-to-protect-ocean-health-by-shaun-seow-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/philanthropy-can-help-unlock-financing-necessary-to-protect-ocean-health-by-shaun-seow-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite growing pressure on marine ecosystems, ocean-health projects often remain underdeveloped because funding, policy, and implementation fail to move in sync. Philanthropy can help change that by aligning priorities, absorbing early risks, and providing the coordinating capacity that enables promising ideas to scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran’s Supreme Leader Is Trapped</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/khamenei-iranian-regime-trapped-between-internal-revolt-and-external-war-by-pegah-banihashemi-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/khamenei-iranian-regime-trapped-between-internal-revolt-and-external-war-by-pegah-banihashemi-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Iran’s supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has built a system that survives only through repression. Yet now, a man who has never been willing to retreat confronts a dilemma from which there is no clean exit: continued internal war against his own people, or an external war that exposes his regime's fragility.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:57:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Authoritarian Illusion</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democracy-is-still-useful-because-lack-of-accountability-blinds-authoritarians-by-jacques-attali-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democracy-is-still-useful-because-lack-of-accountability-blinds-authoritarians-by-jacques-attali-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The debate and uncertainty that are intrinsic to democracies have started to look like weaknesses alongside the order and continuity promised by authoritarian regimes. But democracy is resilient and keeps returning in different forms, simultaneously obsolete and ahead of its time.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe Needs a New Security Framework</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-nato-cannot-guarantee-security-return-to-old-western-eu-necessary-by-carl-bildt-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-nato-cannot-guarantee-security-return-to-old-western-eu-necessary-by-carl-bildt-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent developments have made clear that neither NATO nor the European Union is fully suited to meet the mounting challenges that Europe faces. They have also strengthened the case for reviving the old Western European Union, by institutionalizing the “coalition of the willing” that France, Germany, and the UK have already forged.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:56:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>