<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>The Energy Transition Is Achievable in Emerging Markets</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/energy-transition-emerging-market-economies-is-affordable-by-rakesh-mohan-and-janak-raj-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/energy-transition-emerging-market-economies-is-affordable-by-rakesh-mohan-and-janak-raj-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A decade or so ago, a consensus emerged that the energy transition would require massive amounts of capital. But, according to new research into high-emitting sectors in nine major emerging-market economies, power generation will require the least amount of climate finance to shift from fossil fuels to renewables.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s Rare-Earth Own Goal</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/belief-in-china-rare-earth-dominance-is-based-on-misunderstanding-by-daniel-gros-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/belief-in-china-rare-earth-dominance-is-based-on-misunderstanding-by-daniel-gros-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whereas the conventional wisdom holds that the US depends on Chinese rare earths, putting it at a severe geopolitical disadvantage, it is actually China that depends on the US (and others) for higher value-added rare-earth compounds. Any Chinese restrictions on rare-earth exports are thus likely to hurt China most of all.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:33:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Black Atlantic’s Quest for Reparations</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-black-atlantic-continues-quest-for-reparations-despite-difficult-environment-by-adekeye-adebajo-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-black-atlantic-continues-quest-for-reparations-despite-difficult-environment-by-adekeye-adebajo-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The current geopolitical environment is arguably not conducive to pursuing reparations for slavery and colonialism. But Africa and its diaspora in the Americas, the Caribbean, and Europe continue to make headway, with a focus not only on seeking financial compensation but also on ending racial discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:51:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan’s Iron Lady</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/takaichi-sanae-iron-lady-will-not-improve-gender-relations-japan-by-ian-buruma-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/takaichi-sanae-iron-lady-will-not-improve-gender-relations-japan-by-ian-buruma-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Japan’s first female prime minister, Takaichi Sanae, presents herself as a leader who can be tougher than the men. This, combined with her hawkish views on immigration and defense, suggests that Takaichi will not use her position to help other women crack the glass ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What the Conventional Economic Wisdom Is Missing</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-ai-tech-stocks-and-gold-say-about-the-future-of-the-economy-by-joseph-h-davis-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-ai-tech-stocks-and-gold-say-about-the-future-of-the-economy-by-joseph-h-davis-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While the economic consensus for the US economy anticipates moderate, steady GDP growth and inflation heading toward 2%, the recent strength of both gold and tech stocks is a signal that investors should not ignore. One way or another, structural economic change is coming.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:26:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Many More Cloud Scares Does Europe Need?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/aws-azure-outages-highlight-threat-us-cloud-dominance-poses-to-europe-by-robin-berjon-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/aws-azure-outages-highlight-threat-us-cloud-dominance-poses-to-europe-by-robin-berjon-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Three US companies – Amazon, Google, and Microsoft – now control over 60% of the global cloud market, implying major economic and security risks for Europe. Dismantling these monopolies in the European market, and building sovereign digital infrastructure, is not just possible, but essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Fraught Politics of Corporate Disclosures</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/anti-esg-politics-misses-the-point-material-information-by-raghuram-g-rajan-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/anti-esg-politics-misses-the-point-material-information-by-raghuram-g-rajan-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The US Securities and Exchange Commission must recognize that a wide variety of interests look at corporate financial disclosures, and that the effects of such information can be material in a variety of ways. To reject environmental, social, and governance concerns as political is itself an example of politicization.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Chinese Leaders Really Think of Trump</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinese-view-of-trump-world-disorder-by-mark-leonard-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinese-view-of-trump-world-disorder-by-mark-leonard-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;According to Chinese academics, economists, and retired military officers, the country's leaders are not losing any sleep over Donald Trump's America First agenda. In fact, as they see it, the US president is ushering in a world that Chinese strategists have long been preparing for.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adam Smith and the Moral Economy We Have Lost</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/adam-smith-proper-economics-presupposes-moral-commitments-by-antara-haldar-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/adam-smith-proper-economics-presupposes-moral-commitments-by-antara-haldar-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Smith favored neither state socialism nor unbridled markets, but something subtler: a moral economy grounded in sympathy and the pursuit of human flourishing. In a world where markets look increasingly unmoored from ethics, we could do worse than to revisit what the "founding father" of economics actually wrote.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Can Europe Offer a Fragmenting World?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-update-value-proposition-to-bolster-global-standing-by-ngaire-woods-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-update-value-proposition-to-bolster-global-standing-by-ngaire-woods-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the rivalry between the United States and China intensifies, many countries are seeking partners they can trust. The European Union could fill that role by offering economic opportunity, a secure investment environment, and legal systems that are predictable and fair.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can the Developing World Weather the Next Financial Crisis?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-could-be-hit-hardest-by-future-financial-crisis-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-could-be-hit-hardest-by-future-financial-crisis-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As asset prices soar and speculative money floods into risky markets, the global financial system is slipping back into perilous territory. When the inevitable correction arrives, the fallout will spread far beyond the United States and Europe, hitting developing economies already weighed down by debt and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Argentina Is on a Path to Economic Success</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/javier-mileis-economic-reforms-will-deliver-with-electoral-uncertainty-removed-by-nouriel-roubini-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/javier-mileis-economic-reforms-will-deliver-with-electoral-uncertainty-removed-by-nouriel-roubini-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While many commentators have criticized Argentine President Javier Milei's draconian approach to economic reform, the results of the October legislative election show that the Argentine people would prefer short-term economic pain over a return to Peronist policies. Milei now has a clear path to finish what he started.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:26:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASEAN’s Moment of Truth</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/asean-reforms-to-strengthen-stability-and-prosperity-by-mari-elka-pangestu-and-tan-sri-rebecca-fatimah-sta-maria-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/asean-reforms-to-strengthen-stability-and-prosperity-by-mari-elka-pangestu-and-tan-sri-rebecca-fatimah-sta-maria-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the Asian financial crisis of the 1990s to the COVID-19 pandemic, the bloc has so far risen to the challenges it has faced. But it now confronts its biggest test yet: building balanced partnerships with powerhouses like China, India, Japan, and the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is the Gold Price Telling Us?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-do-record-gold-prices-mean-by-jim-o-neill-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-do-record-gold-prices-mean-by-jim-o-neill-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the price of gold hitting new records and pulling back sharply, is it a bubble or a sign of some profound, broader change in the global financial landscape? While the answer is anyone's guess, history does offer some clues.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Violent New Monroe Doctrine</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-intervention-in-latin-america-reflects-a-new-and-volatile-monroe-doctrine-by-ana-palacio-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-intervention-in-latin-america-reflects-a-new-and-volatile-monroe-doctrine-by-ana-palacio-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US airstrikes in the Caribbean reflect President Donald Trump’s view of intra-American relations as hierarchical. Whereas previous US presidents tried to reconcile Woodrow Wilson’s idealism with Theodore Roosevelt’s realism, Trump merges both impulses into a single, volatile creed: exceptionalism without responsibility or restraint.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:18:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What COP30 Must Do</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cop30-must-follow-financing-commitments-with-concrete-plans-by-syeda-rizwana-hasan-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cop30-must-follow-financing-commitments-with-concrete-plans-by-syeda-rizwana-hasan-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whereas last year’s United Nations Climate Change Conference tripled the global climate-finance target, this year’s gathering must show how funds will be delivered. Developing countries are doing their part, but their climate strategies cannot succeed without external support.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Bessent Right About the Fed?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-bessent-right-about-the-fed-by-willem-h-buiter-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-bessent-right-about-the-fed-by-willem-h-buiter-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The US Federal Reserve and most other G7 central banks have made numerous policy errors this century, making them ripe targets for criticism. But while reforms are necessary to improve their monetary-policy and regulatory performance, that does not mean their independence should be curtailed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Politics Are a Family Business</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-prevalence-of-political-dynasties-lead-to-worse-governance-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-prevalence-of-political-dynasties-lead-to-worse-governance-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The belief that members of political dynasties are uniquely suited to lead is woven deeply into the fabric of Indian governance, from village councils to the highest echelons of parliament. But when elected office is treated like a family heirloom, the quality of governance inevitably suffers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:20:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Lie Behind Trump’s Boat Strikes</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-big-lies-drug-boat-strikes-venezuela-by-timothy-snyder-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-big-lies-drug-boat-strikes-venezuela-by-timothy-snyder-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is training the press and the American people to associate the military strikes on small boats in international waters with stopping the flow of fentanyl and other drugs. This mendacity is a prime example of the falsehoods that imperialists tell before launching doomed wars of aggression.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:40:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Coming US-China Thaw</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-thaw-rare-earths-ban-shows-american-aggression-no-longer-works-by-james-k-galbraith-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-thaw-rare-earths-ban-shows-american-aggression-no-longer-works-by-james-k-galbraith-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of increasingly hostile rhetoric from US officials about China, highly authoritative voices in the United States have suddenly become less hawkish, and the Trump administration has begun to pursue new trade negotiations in earnest. Is the American establishment finally waking up to economic reality?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>