<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>An Overlooked Way to Close Africa’s Health Gaps</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-health-systems-crushing-out-of-pocket-costs-are-preventable-by-ndidi-okonkwo-nwuneli-and-ekhosuehi-iyahen-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-health-systems-crushing-out-of-pocket-costs-are-preventable-by-ndidi-okonkwo-nwuneli-and-ekhosuehi-iyahen-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although remittances from the African diaspora have grown steadily and consistently, their full potential remains untapped, because they usually fund immediate consumption rather than being pooled to drive systemic change. A new social model would make better use of the same funds, starting with health care.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:32:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan Can No Longer Afford Strategic Confusion</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/japan-postwar-strategy-no-longer-viable-by-taniguchi-tomohiko-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/japan-postwar-strategy-no-longer-viable-by-taniguchi-tomohiko-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Japan’s central challenge is often framed in terms of China’s rise, that is only part of the story. Japan’s postwar strategic framework has become obsolete, and this touches on everything from politics and economics to the country’s alliances and even constitutional matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s New Age of Empire</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-new-era-of-imperialism-costs-for-everyone-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-new-era-of-imperialism-costs-for-everyone-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following the United States' illegal intervention in Venezuela, there is a palpable sense of uncertainty and foreboding, particularly among America's traditional allies. But it should already be obvious that things will not end well, either for the US or the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:33:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Now for the “Rules-Based Order”?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-rules-based-order-must-be-built-anew-by-daron-acemoglu-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-rules-based-order-must-be-built-anew-by-daron-acemoglu-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By dropping any pretense of defending democracy or human rights through its intervention in Venezuela, the Trump administration has ripped off the mask and shown the US-led global order to be untenable. To rebuild the idea of rules-based international relations, we will need a new philosophical foundation.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yankee Go Home, Again</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/venezuela-attack-augurs-a-new-era-of-us-intervention-in-latin-america-by-jorge-g-castaneda-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/venezuela-attack-augurs-a-new-era-of-us-intervention-in-latin-america-by-jorge-g-castaneda-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With his attack on Venezuela, US President Donald Trump channeled the US leaders who sought to “liberate” Spain’s former colonies in 1898. But just as the Spanish-American War produced few real gains in the 20th century, Trump's efforts to revive the Monroe Doctrine in the 21st are more ambitious than realistic.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:55:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Major Economies’ Prospects in 2026</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/policy-will-have-little-impact-on-the-performance-of-china-the-us-and-europe-in-2026-by-daniel-gros-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/policy-will-have-little-impact-on-the-performance-of-china-the-us-and-europe-in-2026-by-daniel-gros-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Political leaders tend to claim credit when the economy performs well and to pursue frantic reforms when it does not. But short-term policy measures will have little impact on the forces shaping the prospects of the world’s major economies today.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Hobbesian World Order</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-attack-on-venezuela-implies-a-shift-toward-hobbesian-power-politics-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-attack-on-venezuela-implies-a-shift-toward-hobbesian-power-politics-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With its Venezuela operation, the US has effectively given China an open invitation to invade Taiwan, vindicated Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, and set the stage for more illegal US military actions. Large and rising powers – such as Germany, India, and Japan – must work together to affirm and enforce rules of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Jungle Rules</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-foreign-policy-preying-on-weak-and-vulnerable-by-ian-bremmer-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-foreign-policy-preying-on-weak-and-vulnerable-by-ian-bremmer-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The nature of US foreign policy under the current administration is now clear. America will unilaterally exercise power wherever Donald Trump thinks he can get away with it, uncoupled from the norms, bureaucratic processes, alliance structures, and multilateral institutions that once gave American leadership legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:33:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela and the Future of the West</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-venezuela-intervention-forces-rest-of-west-to-clarify-priorities-by-jim-o-neill-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-venezuela-intervention-forces-rest-of-west-to-clarify-priorities-by-jim-o-neill-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With 2026 barely underway, Donald Trump has pulled the rug out from under anyone who still believed in the salvageability of the old international order. The midnight US raid to capture Venezuela’s president, Nicolás Maduro, confirms that we are in a new era, and the question now is how the rest of the world will respond.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:13:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Limits of Prediction Markets</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/times-person-of-the-year-shows-limits-of-prediction-markets-by-erin-lockwood-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/times-person-of-the-year-shows-limits-of-prediction-markets-by-erin-lockwood-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The question of which bets on &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;’s 2025 Person of the Year should pay out ignited furor on Kalshi and Polymarket, two major prediction markets. By reaching diametrically opposed conclusions, these platforms underscored the indispensable role of human interpretation in settling event contracts, despite claims of automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:32:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overcapacity Is China’s Biggest AI Advantage</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-overcapacity-may-help-it-win-global-ai-race-by-angela-huyue-zhang-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-overcapacity-may-help-it-win-global-ai-race-by-angela-huyue-zhang-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The global AI race will be won not by the power of models and chips, but by how effectively systems can be deployed and improved across the economy. China’s chronic excess capacity, long seen as its greatest weakness, has reduced costs and accelerated adoption, providing the country's AI sector with a decisive edge.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:03:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Looming Population Bust</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/population-aging-declining-fertility-ticking-time-bomb-by-beata-javorcik-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/population-aging-declining-fertility-ticking-time-bomb-by-beata-javorcik-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across much of the world, fertility rates are falling and populations are aging faster than economies can adapt, putting pressure on labor markets, pension systems, and public finances. The challenge is made more difficult to address by growing resistance from older voters and risk-averse leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:30:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Hollowing Out of East Asian Industry</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-competition-from-china-are-hollowing-out-east-asian-industry-by-keun-lee-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-competition-from-china-are-hollowing-out-east-asian-industry-by-keun-lee-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;China’s changing economic structure, together with high and unpredictable US tariffs, has placed Japan and South Korea under intensifying pressure. Only by deepening engagement with each other, and with other reliable partners, can these countries safeguard the industries on which their economies depend.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The End of China’s One-Child Policy, Ten Years Later</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinese-one-child-policy-highlighted-fatal-governance-flaw-by-yi-fuxian-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinese-one-child-policy-highlighted-fatal-governance-flaw-by-yi-fuxian-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The logic behind China’s family-planning policies was always suspect, as were the data that convinced officials to keep them in place long after it should have been clear that they had failed. The history of the 35-year one-child policy highlights a fatal flaw in Chinese governance, for which the country is paying a steep price.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring Pandemic Financing for Middle-Income Countries</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/multilateral-development-banks-must-commit-to-at-risk-funding-next-pandemic-by-masyita-crystallin-and-rachel-glennerster-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/multilateral-development-banks-must-commit-to-at-risk-funding-next-pandemic-by-masyita-crystallin-and-rachel-glennerster-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 pandemic, middle-income countries struggled to invest in vaccines and other medical countermeasures. To avoid repeating the same mistake, policymakers from these countries must demand that multilateral development banks make at-risk financing available as soon as the next outbreak occurs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:41:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe Does Not Lack Capital - It Lacks Scale</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-technological-innovation-suffers-from-lack-of-market-scale-and-incentives-by-antonin-bergeaud-et-al-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-technological-innovation-suffers-from-lack-of-market-scale-and-incentives-by-antonin-bergeaud-et-al-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Even the best startups cannot thrive sustainably in an environment where each country protects its national champions, and where administrative barriers prevent the emergence of truly European ones. If Europe wants to be a technological power, it must finally implement a genuine single market.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:14:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does Venezuela Herald a No-Rules International Order?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-intervention-and-the-international-order-by-carla-norrlof-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-intervention-and-the-international-order-by-carla-norrlof-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The US intervention in Venezuela raises many questions, not just about its legality, but about the international order that the United States has long anchored. Although that order will not suddenly collapse, it will now be costlier and more difficult to sustain.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Economic Transformation Will Be Local</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-economic-transformation-must-be-locally-led-by-gordon-hanson-et-al-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-economic-transformation-must-be-locally-led-by-gordon-hanson-et-al-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it is generating good jobs, navigating the climate transition, stimulating innovation, or building economic resilience, structural transformation is now the name of the game worldwide. While the ends may differ, the means are the same: effective state action, led by subnational governments.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:21:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Ocean Has Finally Entered the Global Climate Debate</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ocean-moved-to-the-mainstream-of-climate-governance-at-cop30-by-kilaparti-ramakrishna-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ocean-moved-to-the-mainstream-of-climate-governance-at-cop30-by-kilaparti-ramakrishna-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The world has started to recognize that the climate’s fate depends on what happens to the ocean. At COP30, ocean-based solutions attracted significant attention and investment, but much more must be done to establish the governance structures required for safeguarding this critical planetary system.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will Japan Be the World’s Next AI Leader?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/will-japan-supportive-regulatory-environment-give-rise-to-ai-leaders-by-hiroshi-mikitani-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/will-japan-supportive-regulatory-environment-give-rise-to-ai-leaders-by-hiroshi-mikitani-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Japan has so far taken an “innovation-first” approach to AI governance, avoiding stringent rules or penalties that could stifle adoption or experimentation. Firms must make the most of this supportive environment to build the tools that can help offset the economic effects of population aging.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>