<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Killing the Goose that Lays the Gold Medal</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-anti-immigration-less-competitive-in-sports-science-other-fields-by-nancy-qian-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-anti-immigration-less-competitive-in-sports-science-other-fields-by-nancy-qian-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Winning the race for global preeminence – whether on the Olympic ice rink or in the laboratory – cannot be achieved by closing off from the world. If America turns talent away, talent will not vanish; it will relocate, and other countries will claim the medals and the breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The End of a Lie</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/mark-carney-abandoning-the-pretense-of-the-rules-based-international-order-by-antara-haldar-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/mark-carney-abandoning-the-pretense-of-the-rules-based-international-order-by-antara-haldar-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In his now-famous speech to this year's gathering of global elites in Davos, Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney rightly drew on a key insight from the late Václav Havel. Institutions fall first in the realm of belief, when people begin abandoning their assigned roles in legitimizing rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:33:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inequality Will Make the Next Pandemic Worse</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/inequality-pandemics-breaking-the-vicious-cycle-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-et-al-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/inequality-pandemics-breaking-the-vicious-cycle-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-et-al-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Crowded living conditions, frontline occupations, and poverty all fuel the spread of pandemics, as do poor nutrition and baseline health characteristics. Unless these issues –&amp;nbsp;which came to define the COVID-19 pandemic –&amp;nbsp;are addressed head-on, the most vulnerable will surely suffer the most in the next crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:31:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>European Security Needs Turkey</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-security-framework-must-include-turkey-by-abdullah-gul-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-security-framework-must-include-turkey-by-abdullah-gul-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the turn that future US administrations take, Europe can no longer rely on American supremacy and goodwill, especially when it comes to its own defense and security. The quest for strategic autonomy has begun, and it should include re-engagement with one of NATO's leading military powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why MAGA Fears Europe</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/why-maga-fears-europe</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/why-maga-fears-europe</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump and his acolytes have long promoted the narrative that the European Union is weak and misguided, and there was no let-up at the World Economic Forum’s annual gathering Davos in January or at this month’s Munich Security Conference. But the truth is that Europe’s social-market model and commitment to openness continue to pay dividends. Far from doubting itself, the EU should double down on its strengths and, as the US-China geopolitical rivalry heats up, tout them as an example for the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:43:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Picture</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-s-fear-and-loathing-of-europe-doc-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-s-fear-and-loathing-of-europe-doc-2026-02</guid><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:42:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuelan Democracy Needs Action, Not Cheap Talk</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-plan-wrongly-puts-oil-before-democracy-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-plan-wrongly-puts-oil-before-democracy-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s Venezuela strategy prioritizes oil reconstruction over elections, treating democracy as an afterthought. But without credible institutions and political legitimacy, Venezuela cannot attract the private capital needed to rebuild its oil sector or provide the legal certainty long-term projects demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:55:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A New Iranian Revolution?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/will-iran-protests-and-trump-pressure-bring-down-islamic-republic-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/will-iran-protests-and-trump-pressure-bring-down-islamic-republic-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amid deepening economic crisis, rising popular discontent, and mounting US pressure, the odds appear to be stacked against the Islamic Republic. Unless Iran's ruling regime embraces a more moderate approach, it may soon face collapse, with destabilizing effects on the entire region.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global Cooperation in a Time of Geopolitical Disruption</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-to-uphold-international-cooperation-amid-return-of-great-power-politics-by-saliem-fakir-and-prabhat-upadhyaya-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-to-uphold-international-cooperation-amid-return-of-great-power-politics-by-saliem-fakir-and-prabhat-upadhyaya-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the rules-based international order breaking down, “minilateralism”  might offer a means of devising new ideas – in particular, for scalable interventions that tangibly improve people’s lives. Without interventions that highlight the benefits of international engagement, broad-based cooperation will remain a hard sell.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quantum Computing Could Fix AI’s Sustainability Problem</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/quantum-computing-solution-to-ai-insatiable-energy-appetite-by-bertrand-badre-et-al-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/quantum-computing-solution-to-ai-insatiable-energy-appetite-by-bertrand-badre-et-al-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As generative AI pushes power grids to their limits, the industry largely favors incremental measures that fail to address underlying issues. The path toward sustainable AI lies in combining quantum computing with energy-efficient application design.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:35:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MAGA’s Approach to Europe Hasn’t Changed</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rubio-colby-maga-message-for-europe-by-mark-leonard-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rubio-colby-maga-message-for-europe-by-mark-leonard-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although the speech that US Secretary of State Marco Rubio delivered to this year’s Munich Security Conference was softer in tone than the one that Vice President JD Vance gave last year, the Europe he celebrated was that of the ethno-nationalist far right. Europe is on its own, and it must start acting like it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:04:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Green Financial Divide Is Growing</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/endangerment-finding-banking-regulation-implications-by-howard-davies-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/endangerment-finding-banking-regulation-implications-by-howard-davies-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By repealing the "endangerment finding" that required US authorities to consider the societal costs of greenhouse-gas emissions, the Trump administration has further reduced the regulatory burden on US banks relative to their peers. For advocates of international competition on a level playing field, it is an unwelcome change.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 11:32:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Superpower Europe</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/european-energy-defense-trade-investment-strategically-aligned-by-nadia-calvino-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/european-energy-defense-trade-investment-strategically-aligned-by-nadia-calvino-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Europe may be a different kind of superpower, given the extent to which it prioritizes values, rules, and multilateralism over sheer might. But it is a superpower nonetheless, and it is increasingly pursuing investments and reforms that will make it not only unassailable but also widely attractive in a dangerous world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The EU Cannot Afford to Bluff on Ukrainian Membership</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-cannot-bluff-on-ukrainian-membership-process-by-laszlo-bruszt-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-cannot-bluff-on-ukrainian-membership-process-by-laszlo-bruszt-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Europe’s debate over the process of making Ukraine a full member is often framed as a test of resolve; but credibility is based as much on capacity as on intent. If promises cannot be sustained politically, they will eventually be broken, and the fallout will be strategically damaging.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:01:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkey’s Lawfare Is a Warning</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/erdogan-detention-of-ekrem-imamoglu-turkey-shows-dangers-of-lawfare-by-bilal-bilici-and-eric-a-baldwin-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/erdogan-detention-of-ekrem-imamoglu-turkey-shows-dangers-of-lawfare-by-bilal-bilici-and-eric-a-baldwin-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The detention of Istanbul Mayor Ekrem İmamoğlu in Turkey is a classic example of democratic backsliding. Using legal institutions and procedures to shape who can run, who can speak, and who can organize has become the preferred method for limiting political competition while retaining the veneer of democracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five US Policy Shifts Could Reshape Financial Markets</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-financial-reforms-could-have-far-reaching-consequences-by-dambisa-moyo-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-financial-reforms-could-have-far-reaching-consequences-by-dambisa-moyo-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s administration is advancing a series of domestic policy changes that affect credit, housing, monetary policy, corporate governance, and digital-asset markets. Taken together, they could transform the regulatory landscape and reverberate through the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe Is Squandering Its Leverage Over China</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-access-to-eu-market-is-undermining-german-competitiveness-by-dalia-marin-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-access-to-eu-market-is-undermining-german-competitiveness-by-dalia-marin-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Requiring Chinese companies that want to sell high-tech products in Europe to form joint ventures with local firms would go a long way toward strengthening the competitiveness of European industry. With its market having become a lifeline for China, the EU needs to recognize the strength of its bargaining position.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:07:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI Will Transform Business, Not Just Jobs</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-will-transform-business-landscape-corporate-structures-by-diane-coyle-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-will-transform-business-landscape-corporate-structures-by-diane-coyle-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Debates about the impact of AI have centered on potential job losses, with far less attention paid to its implications for the business landscape. But corporate leaders should be thinking about how the technology can enhance their organizational capabilities and, in turn, increase economy-wide productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 09:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hope and Disappointment in India</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/can-india-live-up-to-its-enormous-potential-by-kaushik-basu-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/can-india-live-up-to-its-enormous-potential-by-kaushik-basu-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;India’s promise is undeniable, yet political dysfunction and empty rhetoric continue to undermine its long-term prospects. The absence of reliable statistics, lagging innovation, and worsening air quality all point to institutional decay that only sustained, coordinated national action can reverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:07:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Financing the Global South’s Infrastructure Boom</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/financing-global-south-infrastructure-boom-by-rakesh-mohan-and-divya-srinivasan-2026-02</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/financing-global-south-infrastructure-boom-by-rakesh-mohan-and-divya-srinivasan-2026-02</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the Global South, one of the biggest challenges is not just to build more infrastructure, but to build it right. Without institutional capacity and financial depth, the increasingly popular public-private-partnership model can backfire, creating a vicious spiral of debt, delays, and disillusionment.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>