<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Is There Life After the Dollar?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/limits-of-dollar-exorbitant-privilege-in-a-fracturing-world-by-paola-subacchi-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/limits-of-dollar-exorbitant-privilege-in-a-fracturing-world-by-paola-subacchi-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Global financial stability has long depended on the dollar’s role as the main reserve currency, with the expectation that the United States would both set the rules and uphold them. As American leadership grows more erratic, that dependence has become a vulnerability, underscoring the need for a multicurrency system.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:51:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Superintelligence Is Not the Answer to Climate Change</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-superintelligence-will-not-solve-climate-crisis-once-tipping-points-crossed-by-alex-friedman-1-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-superintelligence-will-not-solve-climate-crisis-once-tipping-points-crossed-by-alex-friedman-1-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tech evangelists view climate change as an information problem that the arrival of AI superintelligence will solve, rather than a willpower problem that requires concrete measures, like modernizing the electrical grid and implementing a carbon tax. But there can be no miracle fix once critical planetary tipping points are crossed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Is Serving US Imperialism Raw</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-american-imperialism-unmasked-by-adekeye-adebajo-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-american-imperialism-unmasked-by-adekeye-adebajo-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While previous instances of American gunboat diplomacy often paid lip service to human rights or democracy, Donald Trump has dispensed with idealistic justifications for military intervention abroad. Everyone, not least Europe, now confronts behavior that was already familiar to many across the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain Must Lead the Pushback Against Trump</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/uk-keir-starmer-must-use-good-ties-with-trump-to-defend-nato-greenland-by-william-r-rhodes-and-stuart-p-m-mackintosh-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/uk-keir-starmer-must-use-good-ties-with-trump-to-defend-nato-greenland-by-william-r-rhodes-and-stuart-p-m-mackintosh-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To ensure that Greenland remains a territory of Denmark, British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and other European leaders must put pressure on NATO’s most powerful member. Given the US president’s love of royalty, one way to do that would be to organize a public meeting between British King Charles III and Danish King Frederik X.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Biggest Questions About Venezuelan Oil</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-motivations-for-seizing-controlling-venezuelan-oil-by-anas-alhajji-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-motivations-for-seizing-controlling-venezuelan-oil-by-anas-alhajji-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Some analysts have suggested that Donald Trump seized control of Venezuela’s oil reserves to boost profits for US refineries or to lower energy prices for American consumers by flooding the global market with crude. But this resource grab is most likely motivated by greed, as well as the desire to curb China’s access to energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Is Putting Venezuelan Democracy on Hold</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/machado-must-assert-herself-before-venezuela-democratic-hopes-slip-away-by-piotr-h-kosicki-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/machado-must-assert-herself-before-venezuela-democratic-hopes-slip-away-by-piotr-h-kosicki-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nicolás Maduro’s removal initially raised hopes that Venezuelans would finally regain control over their political future. Instead, US President Donald Trump has chosen to preserve the Chavista power structure, sidelining pro-democracy advocates and leaving opposition leader María Corina Machado with little influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As Climate Diplomacy Stalls, the Economics Are Racing Ahead</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-economics-markets-driving-transition-even-as-politicians-fail-by-julie-mccarthy-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-economics-markets-driving-transition-even-as-politicians-fail-by-julie-mccarthy-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite political gridlock within countries and at global summits, climate change and ecological degradation are creating undeniable economic momentum. As renewables scale up, fossil fuels will become even less competitive; and as ecosystems degrade, markets will price in the risks and reward those who adapt.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:34:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Fight Over the Fed</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-fight-over-the-fed</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-fight-over-the-fed</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The US Federal Reserve’s independence is widely understood to be vital to the economy’s well-being, by insulating monetary policy from political imperatives. But, following the launch of a criminal investigation of Fed Chair Jerome Powell by President Donald Trump’s minions at the Department of Justice, it is hanging on by a thread.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Picture</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-fight-over-the-fed-doc-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-fight-over-the-fed-doc-2026-01</guid><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Petrostate Dilemma in Venezuela</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-removal-of-maduro-will-further-destabilize-venezuela-by-terry-lynn-karl-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-removal-of-maduro-will-further-destabilize-venezuela-by-terry-lynn-karl-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By capturing his Venezuelan counterpart Nicolás Maduro, US President Donald Trump sought to project power abroad but instead exposed his own political vulnerability. Despite his promises to restore Venezuela’s oil industry, his overt resource grab is far more likely to fuel regional turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:11:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The AI Takeover of All Media Is Coming</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ai-takeover-of-media-will-be-sweeping-and-profound-by-charles-ferguson-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ai-takeover-of-media-will-be-sweeping-and-profound-by-charles-ferguson-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not only is AI already upending the filmmaking industry, but Hollywood is just one example of how the technology will cause enormous social and economic pain unless managed humanely and carefully. Fiction writing, commercial photography, radio, music, and – most ominously – journalism and legacy news outlets face a similar reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:31:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Feed Ten Billion People</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/knowledge-and-technologies-to-end-hunger-already-exist-by-yurdi-yasmi-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/knowledge-and-technologies-to-end-hunger-already-exist-by-yurdi-yasmi-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the world’s population expected to reach ten billion by mid-century, agriculture must produce more with less – every season, everywhere. The knowledge and tools to end and prevent food insecurity are already in hand, but they have yet to be used wisely and at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:27:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Impact of Impact Investing</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-investment-undergoing-an-impact-revolution-by-michael-spence-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-investment-undergoing-an-impact-revolution-by-michael-spence-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a venture-capital pioneer and co-founder of Apax Partners, Sir Ronald Cohen experienced firsthand the emergence of an investment framework based on rigorously measured risk and return. How plausible is Cohen's claim that a new revolution is underway, one which adds social, environmental, or development outcomes to the equation?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navigating the Trump-Powell Feud</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-powell-feud-offers-opportunity-to-reaffirm-fed-independence-and-promote-reform-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-powell-feud-offers-opportunity-to-reaffirm-fed-independence-and-promote-reform-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The latest attacks on the US Federal Reserve by Donald Trump's administration are raising fears of a grim future of unanchored inflation expectations, macroeconomic instability, and heightened financial volatility. But internal and external checks and balances are likely to prove sufficiently robust to prevent a major accident.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Happens When Paid Work Disappears?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-and-the-end-of-paid-work-by-peter-g-kirchschlager-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-and-the-end-of-paid-work-by-peter-g-kirchschlager-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of AI is disrupting labor markets at an unprecedented pace, driving down wages and eliminating entire professions faster than new ones can emerge. As data-based systems move into areas once viewed as exclusively human, societies must decide how to preserve dignity when full employment is no longer the norm.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Jerome Powell Had to Say No</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-powell-and-congress-should-respond-to-doj-investigation-into-the-fed-by-gabriel-chodorow-reich-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-powell-and-congress-should-respond-to-doj-investigation-into-the-fed-by-gabriel-chodorow-reich-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whereas the US Federal Reserve’s Marriner S. Eccles stood firm when President Harry Truman sought to finance the Korean War on the cheap, in 1971, Fed Chair Arthur Burns capitulated to pressure to keep interest rates low, fueling years of high inflation. Today's Fed should emulate Eccles – and so should the US Congress.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:46:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s New Old World Order</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-foreign-policy-new-old-world-order-before-world-war-i-by-benn-steil-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-foreign-policy-new-old-world-order-before-world-war-i-by-benn-steil-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Far from being evidence of Donald Trump’s policy schizophrenia, recent developments reflect an administration-wide effort to restore the international order that prevailed before World War I, when America was more restrained in its global ambitions and more secure in its neighborhood. But the costs of such a shift could be profound.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central Asia’s Road to Stability</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/central-asia-fergana-valley-lesson-in-cross-border-stability-by-dan-sleat-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/central-asia-fergana-valley-lesson-in-cross-border-stability-by-dan-sleat-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fergana Valley offers lessons for other regions grappling with conflict and instability. By reopening their borders to each other and cooperating in the management of shared resources, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, and Uzbekistan have turned potential sources of conflict into sites of cooperation benefiting all.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Is Putin Silent on Venezuela?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-putin-thinks-of-the-us-operation-in-venezuela-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-putin-thinks-of-the-us-operation-in-venezuela-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Russian President Vladimir Putin certainly does not relish appearing weak, nor does he want to risk exacerbating tensions with the US. But his willingness to be pushed around has its limits, and it is entirely possible that Donald Trump's administration will prove pushy enough to find out what those limits are.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:05:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Gangster’s-Eye View of Global Power</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-donroe-doctrine-fuels-instability-and-jeopardizes-global-economy-by-jayati-ghosh-2026-01</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-donroe-doctrine-fuels-instability-and-jeopardizes-global-economy-by-jayati-ghosh-2026-01</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At the heart of US President Donald Trump’s foreign policy is the belief that the world can be carved up among major powers, with the United States free to act with impunity in its “backyard.” In reality, this approach is bound to fuel instability, fracture markets, and undermine America’s economic interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:22:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>