<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>China Needs a Consumption Target</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-five-year-plan-must-set-target-for-household-consumption-as-share-of-gdp-by-stephen-s-roach-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-five-year-plan-must-set-target-for-household-consumption-as-share-of-gdp-by-stephen-s-roach-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As Chinese leaders prepare the 15th Five-Year Plan, early signs indicate that it will focus on continuing China’s extraordinary technological ascendancy. But they should be more concerned with boosting consumer demand, which means setting a clear target of raising household consumption to 50% of GDP by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:07:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Trump Achieve Eternal Peace in Gaza?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-gaza-ceasefire-many-questions-unanswered-by-joschka-fischer-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-gaza-ceasefire-many-questions-unanswered-by-joschka-fischer-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is the only power that can succeed as a peacemaker in the Middle East; but that doesn’t mean the task will be easy. The question now is whether US President Donald Trump has the patience and stamina that brokering a lasting political resolution between Israelis and Palestinians requires.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Trump Administration’s Latest Assault on Workers</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-refusal-to-defend-ban-on-non-compete-clauses-hurts-workers-by-sandeep-vaheesan-and-alvaro-bedoya-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-refusal-to-defend-ban-on-non-compete-clauses-hurts-workers-by-sandeep-vaheesan-and-alvaro-bedoya-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024, the US Federal Trade Commission freed millions of Americans from a powerful constraint on their labor-market mobility by banning non-compete clauses for most workers. It was one of the biggest policy wins for American workers in recent years – and, because of Donald Trump's administration, it may never take effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Perils of Economic Centrism in a Polarized World</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/loneliness-of-the-centrist-economist-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/loneliness-of-the-centrist-economist-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Few ideas in economics have been as misrepresented as the link between debt and growth. More than a decade ago, a prominent analysis was falsely cast as a call for austerity when, in fact, it showed something far more mundane: countries burdened by heavy debt often have limited room to invest or respond when crises strike.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Geopolitical Significance of Historical Precedent</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/historical-precedents-for-geopolitical-uncertainty-can-help-shape-response-by-jacques-attali-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/historical-precedents-for-geopolitical-uncertainty-can-help-shape-response-by-jacques-attali-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The cycle of rise and decline over the centuries has established some basic tenets of power, including that civilizations can still collapse even when they are set up for success. This lesson is relevant for today’s world, in which short-termism and populism risk derailing what should be a bright future.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:10:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The German Economic Miracle, Then and Now</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/german-postwar-economic-miracle-revisited-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/german-postwar-economic-miracle-revisited-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Why did Germany, defeated in both World War I and WWII, recover so strongly after the latter, but not after the former? Two new books suggest that conventional accounts of the Wirtschaftswunder – West Germany’s miraculous economic ascent after WWII – get it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:42:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine Needs a “Victory First” Aid Strategy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-allies-must-finance-military-defense-spending-by-anastassia-fedyk-et-al-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-allies-must-finance-military-defense-spending-by-anastassia-fedyk-et-al-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Western countries have been generous in supporting Ukraine since Russia’s full-scale invasion in 2022, their financial assistance can be used only for non-military purposes. Instead of deploying aid this way, which creates distortions that undermine Ukraine’s war effort, foreign donors should directly fund defense spending.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Africans Want from COP30</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-must-present-a-united-front-at-cop30-by-carlos-lopes-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-must-present-a-united-front-at-cop30-by-carlos-lopes-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of continuing to wait for aid, Africa is seeking to mobilize investment in its green transition, not because rich countries “owe” Africans – though they do – but because Africa can help the world tackle climate change. Success will require progress on four fronts, all of which will be addressed at COP30.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Vatican’s Voice of Reason on AI</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/vatican-ai-dialogues-rare-ethical-voice-of-reason-by-anne-bouverot-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/vatican-ai-dialogues-rare-ethical-voice-of-reason-by-anne-bouverot-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the Holy See to weigh in on a topic like AI may seem unexpected. But the Catholic Church has a venerable tradition of leadership on pressing technological and social issues, and it is uniquely positioned to influence public debate and policymaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Balancing Ethics and AI Innovation</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-governance-requires-finding-a-balance-between-ethics-and-innovation-by-j-p-singh-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-governance-requires-finding-a-balance-between-ethics-and-innovation-by-j-p-singh-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Disregarding ethical considerations in the name of AI innovation – the direction taken by the US – is a recipe for disaster. But pretending that lofty ethical principles will solve the real governance challenges AI raises is similarly misguided.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:12:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Xi’s Purges Reveal His Insecurity</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/xi-military-purges-expose-his-insecurity-and-raise-risks-for-china-by-brahma-chellaney-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/xi-military-purges-expose-his-insecurity-and-raise-risks-for-china-by-brahma-chellaney-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From surveilling and repressing Chinese citizens to firing and prosecuting potential rivals, Chinese President Xi Jinping seems able to rule only through fear. But fear is not a foundation for long-term stability, and the more Xi seeks to consolidate power, the more vulnerable his position becomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Norway’s War Profiteering Could Help Ukraine</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/norway-should-guarantee-eu-ukraine-loan-secured-by-russian-assets-by-havard-halland-3-and-knut-anton-mork-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/norway-should-guarantee-eu-ukraine-loan-secured-by-russian-assets-by-havard-halland-3-and-knut-anton-mork-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the European Union tries to put together a large loan for Ukraine, sovereign guarantees and the risk they pose to member states' credit ratings have become a stumbling block. Fortunately, having raked in tens of billions of dollars from the fallout of Russia's invasion, Norway could break the impasse.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:28:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Global Majority’s Fight for Economic Justice</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/peoples-summit-for-global-economic-justice-at-g20-meeting-south-africa-by-sekoetlane-phamodi-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/peoples-summit-for-global-economic-justice-at-g20-meeting-south-africa-by-sekoetlane-phamodi-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amid a series of cascading crises, civil-society groups and NGOs from across the Global South will meet with their Global North allies on the sidelines of the upcoming G20 Leaders’ Summit in Johannesburg. The aim is to develop a locally rooted but globally connected program of action for achieving economic justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:26:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supply-Chain Economics Beats Tariff Politics</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-will-pay-price-for-misunderstanding-supply-chain-dynamics-by-jun-du-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-will-pay-price-for-misunderstanding-supply-chain-dynamics-by-jun-du-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty years ago, China learned the hard way that once supply chains reorganize, they never return to their previous form. By relying on tariffs and subsidies, the United States is now paying the price for underestimating how tightly its economy is bound to the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:37:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Product Scorecards Can Help Rescue Europe’s Green Deal</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/a-product-level-approach-to-sustainability-reporting-can-save-the-eu-green-deal-by-brian-hill-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/a-product-level-approach-to-sustainability-reporting-can-save-the-eu-green-deal-by-brian-hill-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Europe’s competitiveness concerns are understandable, inaction on social and environmental challenges also carries high economic costs. Rather than resign itself to stifling its nascent sustainability-disclosure regime under pressure from the US, the EU should devise a new system based on products, not industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 15:01:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Does the Market Really Think About AI?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-economic-potential-what-markets-are-really-saying-by-isaiah-andrews-and-maryam-farboodi-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-economic-potential-what-markets-are-really-saying-by-isaiah-andrews-and-maryam-farboodi-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite all the enthusiasm for AI, which has undoubtedly demonstrated impressive capabilities, the signal from bond markets suggests that investors are unconvinced that the technology will generate sustained or widespread growth, let alone a more extreme positive or negative outcome. What accounts for this disconnect?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:42:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Measuring AI’s Economic Impact</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-ai-boom-real-or-just-another-speculative-bubble-by-diane-coyle-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-ai-boom-real-or-just-another-speculative-bubble-by-diane-coyle-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the hype and vast sums pouring into AI, we still lack convincing evidence that it is transforming the global economy or boosting productivity and growth. Without reliable data on its uses and benefits, we cannot tell whether we are witnessing a genuine transformation or yet another speculative bubble.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Right Way to Finance Ukraine’s Defense</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/russian-frozen-assets-reparations-loan-to-ukraine-by-vladyslav-rashkovan-and-greg-wilson-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/russian-frozen-assets-reparations-loan-to-ukraine-by-vladyslav-rashkovan-and-greg-wilson-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Supporting Ukraine with a reparations loan drawing on frozen Russian funds is the right choice not only morally, financially, and legally, but also politically. With Ukraine's economy devastated by the exogenous shock of Russian aggression, Western leaders have a chance to show that they are equal to the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public AI Is the New Multilateralism</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/public-ai-can-be-the-basis-of-new-international-cooperation-by-jacob-taylor-3-and-joshua-tan-1-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/public-ai-can-be-the-basis-of-new-international-cooperation-by-jacob-taylor-3-and-joshua-tan-1-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1970s, European governments worked together to create an aircraft manufacturer capable of competing with the US firm Boeing. As a handful of private companies in Shenzhen and Silicon Valley race to entrench their AI dominance, similarly bold cooperation among middle powers has become imperative.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The New “China Shock” Is Hitting Poor Countries the Hardest</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-manufacturing-surplus-costs-for-low-middle-income-countries-by-shoumitro-chatterjee-1-and-arvind-subramanian-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-manufacturing-surplus-costs-for-low-middle-income-countries-by-shoumitro-chatterjee-1-and-arvind-subramanian-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;China’s continued dominance in low-skill export sectors reflects not just efficiency, but deliberate policy choices that prevent poorer countries from climbing the development ladder. If it truly aspires to global leadership, it must stop tilting the playing field in its own favor.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:15:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>