<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Silicon Valley Socialism</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-socialism-from-above-basic-income-with-disempowerment-by-noreena-hertz-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-socialism-from-above-basic-income-with-disempowerment-by-noreena-hertz-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tech titans like Elon Musk are offering us a future of socialism from above, where they keep the means of production while everyone else gets an allowance. But if the allowance is high enough, should we care who owns the algorithms and data centers?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:42:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The West Is Not Ready for a Multipolar World</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/west-not-ready-multipolar-world-of-emerging-powers-china-india-brics-by-gemma-chenger-deng-and-jim-o-neill-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/west-not-ready-multipolar-world-of-emerging-powers-china-india-brics-by-gemma-chenger-deng-and-jim-o-neill-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The world is shifting from a largely hegemonic international system to a more fragmented, contested, and multipolar set of arrangements. In this environment, the central question for the West is not how to revive a dying order, but how to operate credibly and responsibly in one where influence must be shared.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate Adaptation More Than Covers Its Cost</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-adaptation-costs-and-benefits-for-2-degree-scenario-by-mekala-krishnan-et-al-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-adaptation-costs-and-benefits-for-2-degree-scenario-by-mekala-krishnan-et-al-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Effective climate adaptation can strengthen countries’ resilience, protect vulnerable communities, and support economic growth. But while the world has the tools, the level of investment needed to close today’s adaptation gap, let alone to address likely future needs, has fallen far short.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 09:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Against Euro-Pessimism</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/against-europessimism-political-reinvention-possible-in-face-of-russia-us-threats-by-harold-james-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/against-europessimism-political-reinvention-possible-in-face-of-russia-us-threats-by-harold-james-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, Europe has become an unseemly hybrid: a punching bag and a laughingstock. But even if recent events make it difficult to feel optimistic, the continent's history offers plenty of reminders that reinvention and recovery are the rule, not the exception.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Tax AI</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-hours-level-tax-computational-time-usage-by-sami-mahroum-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-hours-level-tax-computational-time-usage-by-sami-mahroum-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By responding to economic insecurity with increasingly blunt tools like minimum-wage hikes, policymakers are overlooking the deeper problem: the accelerating decoupling of human labor time from economic value. The only solution is to recognize machine time as a distinct production input and price it accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:45:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the World Can Reboot America First</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-g20-presidency-should-embrace-win-win-logic-by-vera-songwe-and-bernice-lee-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-g20-presidency-should-embrace-win-win-logic-by-vera-songwe-and-bernice-lee-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Donald Trump does not much care about building a better, fairer world, it might be possible to harness his self-interest to the cause of building one. His administration’s statements and policies point to several areas where the US just might be willing to support broadly beneficial transformations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Humanity’s Alignment Problem</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-climate-risks-are-about-misalignment-not-lack-of-knowledge-by-antara-haldar-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-climate-risks-are-about-misalignment-not-lack-of-knowledge-by-antara-haldar-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The defining question of the 21st century is no longer whether humanity can build extraordinary systems, but whether we can align them – technically, institutionally, and morally – before they slip out of our control. Given recent trends in AI and climate governance, we have our work cut out for us.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Real Existential Threat Facing Europe</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-most-serious-problem-not-immigration-but-technological-backwardness-by-nouriel-roubini-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-most-serious-problem-not-immigration-but-technological-backwardness-by-nouriel-roubini-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what far-right leaders claim, Europe’s greatest challenge is not immigration or “wokeness,” but its own economic and technological backwardness. With productivity growth lagging and innovation increasingly taking place elsewhere, Europe must confront its structural weaknesses or risk falling further behind.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Country and a World Out of Balance</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-and-a-world-out-of-balance-by-richard-haass-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-and-a-world-out-of-balance-by-richard-haass-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump's second administration has stood out for its unconstrained assertion of executive primacy and a foreign policy that has shifted geopolitical power in favor of Russia and China. Will American democracy right itself in 2026, the year it turns 250?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:13:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Decisive Year for Ocean Conservation</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/2025-landmark-year-for-ocean-conservation-blue-economy-by-peter-thomson-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/2025-landmark-year-for-ocean-conservation-blue-economy-by-peter-thomson-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the global retreat from multilateralism, international efforts to protect the ocean gained momentum in 2025, leading to some landmark decisions. To build on this progress, policymakers must fully implement these new agreements and treaties, and all stakeholders must quickly mobilize more finance.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:07:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Haven’t Trump’s Tariffs Crashed the US Economy?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariff-impact-on-us-inflation-and-real-incomes-could-materialize-in-2026-by-jeffrey-frankel-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariff-impact-on-us-inflation-and-real-incomes-could-materialize-in-2026-by-jeffrey-frankel-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While Donald Trump followed through on his campaign promise to raise tariffs sharply in 2025, the domestic economic impact was not as bad as many had feared. But there is good reason to think that the tariffs' adverse impact on inflation and employment was merely delayed – and could materialize with full force in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:19:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s Post-Trump China Strategy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-must-start-planning-for-post-trump-engagement-with-china-by-stephen-s-roach-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-must-start-planning-for-post-trump-engagement-with-china-by-stephen-s-roach-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although diplomacy has long been at the forefront of Sino-American engagement, the rise of politically constrained, egocentric leaders, coupled with new strains of nationalism in the United States and China, has rendered it ineffective. But it is not too soon to start considering a new architecture of engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will Dollar Dominance Survive Digital Money?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/to-preserve-dollar-dominance-us-must-build-the-rails-through-which-digital-money-moves-by-silvia-sgherri-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/to-preserve-dollar-dominance-us-must-build-the-rails-through-which-digital-money-moves-by-silvia-sgherri-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Depending on how they are designed, the rails conveying digital money can underpin an open monetary system or entrench a bipolar system of competing blocs with incompatible standards. For the US, continued global monetary leadership will require upgrading domestic and cross-border payment infrastructure for interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Donald Trump and the White Man’s Burden in Nigeria</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-threats-to-invade-nigeria-reflect-colonizers-civilizing-mission-by-adekeye-adebajo-2025-12-1-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-threats-to-invade-nigeria-reflect-colonizers-civilizing-mission-by-adekeye-adebajo-2025-12-1-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump has made good on his threat to take military action against Nigeria to save Christians from a “genocide.” Trump has three possible motives: his mercantilist quest for rare-earth minerals, his pandering to evangelical Christians, and his racist grievances.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PS Commentators’ Predictions for 2026</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ps-commentators-predictions-for-2026-by-ps-editors-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ps-commentators-predictions-for-2026-by-ps-editors-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump’s second presidency has reset global expectations, making uncertainty the defining feature of today’s geopolitical and economic landscape. While the path forward remains unclear, the year ahead will likely be marked by greater geopolitical and financial turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europeans Are All Peronists Now</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-implement-necessary-reforms-budget-cuts-to-avoid-argentina-fate-by-cristina-ramirez-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-implement-necessary-reforms-budget-cuts-to-avoid-argentina-fate-by-cristina-ramirez-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;European voters increasingly resemble their Argentinian counterparts, who, until recently, believed the unsustainable promises offered by Peronist politicians. To avoid the economic shock therapy that has befallen Argentina, Europe’s leaders must be willing to make hard choices, and electorates must be willing to reward them for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gen Z Is Making Politics Hopeful Again</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/young-people-are-demanding-future-worth-living-by-ngaire-woods-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/young-people-are-demanding-future-worth-living-by-ngaire-woods-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fueled by anger over corruption, high living costs, and narrowing opportunities, youth-led protests have been sweeping the developing world. Rather than seeking to upend political systems, activists are calling for governments that deliver economic security, accountability, and climate action.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump Has an Affordability Problem</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-affordability-problem-assigning-blame-by-michael-r-strain-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-affordability-problem-assigning-blame-by-michael-r-strain-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although Americans are rightly worried about inflation and the affordability of basic goods and services, much of the commentary on the issue has offered more heat than light. How much blame does the president deserve, and what could he do to stave off electoral disaster in November 2026?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:19:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Fed Became a Lender of Immediate Resort</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-mission-creep-undermines-its-legitimacy-by-amit-seru-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-mission-creep-undermines-its-legitimacy-by-amit-seru-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With each crisis over the past 15 years, the Federal Reserve has expanded the scope and scale of its interventions. This gradual mission creep has blurred the line between routine liquidity support and support for insolvent institutions, undermining the very purpose of central-bank independence.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rogue Hegemons Are Sabotaging the Global Economy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-chinese-mercantilism-upending-global-trading-system-by-arvind-subramanian-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-chinese-mercantilism-upending-global-trading-system-by-arvind-subramanian-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than providing global public goods, the United States and China are inflicting global economic costs –&amp;nbsp;in mutually reinforcing ways. Donald Trump's tariffs have exacerbated Chinese mercantilism, and Chinese exports are provoking developing countries to engage in protectionism of their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:51:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>