<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Europe Should Stand with Japan on Taiwan</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-should-join-japan-in-committing-to-punish-china-for-invading-taiwan-by-jonas-parello-plesner-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-should-join-japan-in-committing-to-punish-china-for-invading-taiwan-by-jonas-parello-plesner-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just as Russian President Vladimir Putin was clear about his intentions toward Ukraine, Chinese President Xi Jinping has left no doubt about his plans for Taiwan. The only way to deter him from pursuing "reunification" with the island is to make clear that the costs of doing so will be punishing.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:59:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deporting American Democracy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-domestic-repression-may-fuel-foreign-aggression-by-timothy-snyder-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-domestic-repression-may-fuel-foreign-aggression-by-timothy-snyder-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The instability caused by the Nazis' mass deportations and Kristallnacht in the autumn of 1938 was unpopular in Germany – much as ICE raids are unpopular in US cities. For the Nazis, the radical next steps were possible only under cover of war – which may be true for US President Donald Trump as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:53:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy’s Gold Gambit</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/italy-gold-ownership-amendment-could-destabilize-the-eurozone-by-lucrezia-reichlin-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/italy-gold-ownership-amendment-could-destabilize-the-eurozone-by-lucrezia-reichlin-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By proclaiming that Italy's official gold reserves –&amp;nbsp;the world's third largest – belong to "the Italian people," Giorgia Meloni's government is essentially highlighting its contingency plan for a major crisis. At a time of declining confidence in European institutions, that is the last thing the eurozone needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Keep Nigeria’s Schoolchildren Safe</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/nigeria-needs-global-funding-to-make-schools-safer-by-gordon-brown-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/nigeria-needs-global-funding-to-make-schools-safer-by-gordon-brown-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Too many Nigerian students have had their education interrupted by terrorism and kidnapping for ransom. If parents are to allow their children to return to school in the new year, adequate security infrastructure, clear communication protocols, and effective early-warning systems will be needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will the Fed Be Allowed to Do Its Job?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/trump-has-already-undermined-fed-independence-with-macro-risks-multiplying-by-gary-gensler-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/trump-has-already-undermined-fed-independence-with-macro-risks-multiplying-by-gary-gensler-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Less than one year into his second term, Donald Trump has already begun to undermine the US Federal Reserve’s independence, introducing risks unseen since the 1970s. For the sake of the global economy, we should all hope that the next chair still has the space – and the resolve – to serve the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China and America Must Get Serious About AI Risk</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/china-us-ai-risks-call-for-urgent-diplomacy-by-jake-sullivan-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/china-us-ai-risks-call-for-urgent-diplomacy-by-jake-sullivan-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;China and America will continue to compete vigorously for the lead in AI. But as the world’s two – and only – AI superpowers, both countries urgently need to engage one another directly to address the growing list of dangers that the technology poses to markets, infrastructure, social stability, and humanity itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why China Can’t Win the AI-Led Industrial Revolution</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/why-china-cannot-win-ai-race-by-di-guo-and-chenggang-xu-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/why-china-cannot-win-ai-race-by-di-guo-and-chenggang-xu-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;History has consistently shown that industrial revolutions require free institutions and robust demand to support ongoing entrepreneurship and the commercialization of new, productivity-enhancing products and services. With its system of totalitarian party-state rule, China checks none of these boxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Crypto an Opportunity or a Threat?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/crypto-from-bitcoin-to-stablecoins-all-ultimately-threat-to-social-financial-stability-by-jean-tirole-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/crypto-from-bitcoin-to-stablecoins-all-ultimately-threat-to-social-financial-stability-by-jean-tirole-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Innovation should enhance economic fundamentals, not erode them. With enthusiasm for crypto remaining strong, speculative unbacked tokens and lightly regulated stablecoins must be contained before they threaten financial stability and become part of the shadow banking sector.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Is Canceling the Rule of Law – and US Democracy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/trump-end-of-rule-of-law-means-end-of-american-democracy-by-aziz-huq-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/trump-end-of-rule-of-law-means-end-of-american-democracy-by-aziz-huq-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not only has the second Trump administration shown an utter contempt for the rule of law, but so too have its allies in Congress and on the Supreme Court. The bedrock principle that has long defined and sustained the American democratic project is being shredded before our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latin America’s New Birth of Democracy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/latin-america-new-birth-of-democracy-by-enrique-krauze-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/latin-america-new-birth-of-democracy-by-enrique-krauze-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The populist wave that crashed over several Latin American countries not so long ago now may be retreating. Across the region, people are waking up to their rulers’ lies and misdeeds and rediscovering the liberal, republican values that defined earlier periods of their history.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel Unbound</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/israel-unbound-implications-for-middle-east-by-vali-nasr-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/israel-unbound-implications-for-middle-east-by-vali-nasr-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While the United States and its allies finally led a push to end the Gaza war in 2025, it is not clear how regional stability will be restored, or what shape a new regional order will assume. For the foreseeable future, the Middle East will be bracing for a prolonged conflict as Israel pursues military supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gambling With the Dollar’s Future</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/us-trump-administration-gambling-dollars-future-by-carmen-m-reinhart-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/us-trump-administration-gambling-dollars-future-by-carmen-m-reinhart-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While there is no immediate candidate to supplant the US dollar, ballooning US deficits, the risk of higher US inflation, and the fragmentation of global trade have complicated the picture. In this environment, US policymakers' complacency about America's "exorbitant privilege" seems dangerously unjustified.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Year That Could Be</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/year-ahead-2026-by-lea-ypi-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/year-ahead-2026-by-lea-ypi-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A decade after Brexit and Donald Trump's first election to the US presidency, states are increasingly isolated from one another, institutions are held hostage to the arbitrary will of individuals, and the rule of law seems irreversibly in decline. Yet even without cause for optimism, one can – and must – muster hope.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A New Age of Nuclear Proliferation?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/new-age-of-nuclear-proliferation-by-mohamed-elbaradei-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/new-age-of-nuclear-proliferation-by-mohamed-elbaradei-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not only are major nuclear-weapon states failing to pursue arms control and disarmament; they are openly doubling down on "modernizing" and expanding their arsenals to match their increasingly bellicose rhetoric. Fragile global structures that are supposed to prevent our self-annihilation are crumbling before our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump and the End of American Hegemony</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/trump-end-of-american-hegemony-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/trump-end-of-american-hegemony-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Donald Trump's erratic, unlawful policies upended the postwar era of globalization and set in motion a process that will culminate in America's loss of global primacy. Not only are the sources of US economic strength being destroyed, but all other countries are de-risking from America as fast as they can.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Filling America’s Shoes</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/us-global-leadership-waning-who-can-or-will-fill-its-shoes-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/us-global-leadership-waning-who-can-or-will-fill-its-shoes-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the United States cutting aid, scrapping international agreements, and waging war on rules-based systems and arrangements that it built, questions about the future of the global order have gained new urgency. Though America may be replaceable in some areas, others may become a new Wild West.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Give Ukraine Back Its Future</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/west-must-support-victory-strategy-for-ukraine-by-chrystia-freeland-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/west-must-support-victory-strategy-for-ukraine-by-chrystia-freeland-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There is more than a little irony in the fact that Ukrainians are bleeding and dying for Western democracy and the European Union at a time when so many are losing faith in both. But they are –&amp;nbsp;and they have shown that they can win.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>“Never Again,” Again</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/us-europe-must-not-allow-collapse-of-postwar-order-by-radoslaw-sikorski-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/us-europe-must-not-allow-collapse-of-postwar-order-by-radoslaw-sikorski-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The West is facing its greatest challenge in decades. The postwar order that was shaped by the trauma of World War II and the Holocaust, and built on a foundation of political compromise, respect for other countries’ sovereignty, free markets, civil liberties, and minority protections, is now at risk of collapsing.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asia Adrift, Asia Alone</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/asian-democracies-adapting-to-trump-withdrawal-and-hostility-by-akihisa-nagashima-2025-11</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/asian-democracies-adapting-to-trump-withdrawal-and-hostility-by-akihisa-nagashima-2025-11</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just as Asian democracies had to adapt to a long period of economic and geopolitical uncertainty following the American withdrawal from Vietnam 50 years ago, now they must do so again. Donald Trump's return has forced the region to pursue self-reliance and new, mutually beneficial economic arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Peace Together</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/no-substitute-for-international-partnership-in-building-peace-by-yvette-cooper-2025-12</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/no-substitute-for-international-partnership-in-building-peace-by-yvette-cooper-2025-12</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It is all too easy for world leaders to turn away from conflicts where there is no simple solution, or crises where there is no quick fix. But in today's world, from the Middle East and Ukraine to Myanmar and Sudan, that would leave few conflicts and crises to address.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>